<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="decompress16x16.png" type="Other"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Decompress Files (Labs)</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Unpacks and decompresses files from an archive.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node unpacks and decompresses files from archives. The path to the extracted
			files
			will
			be contained in the output table.
			<br />
			<br />
			Supported formats are:
			<ul>
				<li>.zip</li>
				<li>.jar</li>
				<li>.tar</li>
				<li>.tar.gz</li>
				<li>.tar.bz2</li>
				<li>.cpio</li>
				<li>.ar</li>
			</ul>
		</intro>

<option name="Read from">
			Select a file system from which you want to unzip your archive or decompress your snappy file. There are four default file system
			options to choose from:
			<br />
			<ul>
				<li>
					<i>Local File System:</i>
					Allows you to delete a file/folder from your local system.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Mountpoint:</i>
					Allows you to unpack and decompress an archive on a mountpoint. When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to 
					choose the mountpoint. Unconnected mountpoints are grayed out but can still be selected (note that
					browsing is disabled in this case). Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable
					browsing. A mountpoint is displayed in red, if it was previously selected but is no longer 
					available. You won't be able to save the dialog as long as you don't select a valid i.e. known
					mountpoint.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Relative to:</i>
					Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path to an archive file relative to the current
					mountpoint, current workflow or the current workflow's data area. When selected a new drop-down menu
					appears to choose which of the three options to use.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i> 
					Allows to specify a URL (e.g. file://, http:// or knime:// protocol). 
	                 When selected, a spinner appears that allows you to specify the desired connection and write timeout in milliseconds.
	                 In case it takes longer to connect to the host / write the file, the node fails to execute.
	                 Browsing is disabled for this option.
	            </li>
			</ul>
			To read from other file systems, click on <b>...</b> in the bottom left corner of the node icon followed by
			<i>Add ports</i> and <i>Source file system connection</i>. Afterwards, connect the desired file system connector node to the
			newly added input port. The file system connection will then be shown in the drop-down menu. It is grayed
			out if the file system is not connected in which case you have to (re)execute the connector node first.
			Note: The default file systems listed above can't be selected if a file system is provided via the input
			port.
		</option>
		<option name="File/URL">
			Enter a URL when decompressing a file specified by <i>Custom/KNIME URL</i>, otherwise enter a path to an archive file. The
				required syntax of a path depends on the chosen file system, such as &quot;C:\path\to\file&quot; (Local
				File System on Windows) or  &quot;/path/to/file&quot; (Local
	            File System on Linux/MacOS and Mountpoint). For file systems connected via input port, the node
	            description of the respective connector node describes the required path format.
				You can also choose a previously selected folder from the drop-down list, or select a location
				from the &quot;Browse...&quot; dialog.
				Note that browsing is disabled in some cases:
				<ul>
					<li><i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i> Browsing is always disabled.</li>
					<li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Browsing is disabled if the selected mountpoint isn't connected.
					Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.</li>
					<li><i>File systems provided via input port:</i>
					Browsing is disabled if the connector node hasn't been executed since the workflow has been opened.
					(Re)execute the connector node to enable browsing.</li>
				</ul>
		</option>
		<option name="Write to">
				Select a file system to which you want to extract your files.
				There are three default file system options to choose from:
				<br />
				<ul>
					<li><i>Local File System:</i> Allows you to select a folder on your
	                    local system.
	                </li>
	                <li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Allows you to write to a mountpoint.
	                	When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to choose the mountpoint.
	                	Unconnected mountpoints are greyed out but can still be selected (note that browsing is disabled in this case).
	                	Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.
	                	A mountpoint is displayed in red if it was previously selected but is no longer available.
	                	You won't be able to save the dialog as long as you don't select a valid i.e. known mountpoint.
	                </li>
	                <li><i>Relative to:</i> Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path
						relative to the current mountpoint, current workflow or the current workflow's data area.
	                When selected a new drop-down menu appears to choose which of the three options to use.
	                </li>
				</ul>
				It is possible to use other file systems with this node. Therefore,
				you have to enable the file system connection input port of this
				node
				by clicking the
				<b>...</b>
				in the bottom left corner of the node's icon and choose
				<i>Add ports</i> followed by <i>Destination file system connection</i>
				.
				<br />
				Afterwards, you can simply connect the desired connector node to this node.
				The file system connection will then be shown in the drop-down menu.
				It is grayed out if the file system is not connected in which case you have to (re)execute the connector node first.
				Note: The default file systems listed above can't be selected if a file system is provided via the input port.
			</option>
		<option name="Folder">
			Enter a valid directory path where the files should get extracted to. The
				required syntax of a path depends on the chosen file system, such as &quot;C:\path\to\file&quot; (Local
				File System on Windows) or  &quot;/path/to/file&quot; (Local
	            File System on Linux/MacOS and Mountpoint). For file systems connected via input port, the node
	            description of the respective connector node describes the required path format.
				You can also choose a previously selected folder from the drop-down list, or select a location
				from the &quot;Browse...&quot; dialog.
				Note that browsing is disabled in some cases:
				<ul>
					<li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Browsing is disabled if the selected mountpoint isn't connected.
					Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.</li>
					<li><i>File systems provided via input port:</i>
					Browsing is disabled if the connector node hasn't been executed since the workflow has been opened.
					(Re)execute the connector node to enable browsing.</li>
				</ul>
		</option>
		<option name="Create missing folders">Select if the folders of the selected
				output
				location should be created if they do not already exist. If
				this
				option is unchecked, the node will fail if a folder does not
				exist.
			</option>
			<option name="If exists">
				Specify the behavior of the node in case an output file already exists.
				<ul>
					<li><i>Overwrite:</i> Will replace any existing file.
					</li>
					<li><i>Ignore:</i> Will ignore existing files and append a column in the output table which tells, if a file was newly created or not.
					</li>
					<li><i>Fail:</i> Will issue an error during the node's execution (to prevent unintentional overwrite).
					</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0" name="Source File System Connection"
			group-identifier="Source File System Connection">
			The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0" name="Destination File System Connection"
			group-identifier="Destination File System Connection">
			The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<outPort name="Output table" index="0">
			Table containing the list of files and folders that have been extracted.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
