<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./manipulator.png" type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Table Manipulator</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Allows to perform several transformations on any number of input tables such
		as renaming, filtering, re-ordering and type changing of the input columns. If more than one input table
		is available the node concatenates all input rows into a single result table.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
        Allows to perform several column transformations on any number of input tables such
        as renaming, filtering, re-ordering and type changing of the input columns.
        <p>If more than one input table is available the node concatenates all input rows into a single result table. 
        If the input tables contain the same RowID the node can either generate a new RowID
        or prepend the input table index to the original RowID of the corresponding input table. 
        </p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Use existing RowID">
			Check this box if the RowIDs from the input tables should be used for the
			output tables. If unchecked, a new RowID is generated.
			The generated RowID follows the schema "Row0", "Row1" and so on.
		</option>
		<option name="Prepend table index to RowID">
			Only enabled if the existing RowIDs are used. If checked, a prefix is
			prepended to the RowIDs that indicates which table the row came
			from.
			The format of the prefix is "Table_0_", "Table_1_" and so on.
		</option>
		<option name="Transformations">
			This option displays every column as a row in a table that allows modifying
			the structure of the output table.
			It supports reordering, filtering and renaming columns. It is also
			possible to change the type of the columns.
			Reordering is done via drag-and-drop. Just drag a column to the position it
			should have in the output table.
			Whether and where to add unknown columns during execution is specified via
			the special row &lt;any unknown new column&gt;.
		</option>
		<option name="Reset order">Resets the order of columns to the order in the
			input input tables.</option>
		<option name="Reset filter">Clicking this button will reset the filters i.e.
			all columns will be included.</option>
		<option name="Reset names">Resets the names to the names that are read from
			file or created if the file/folder doesn't contain column names.
		</option>
		<option name="Reset types">Resets the output types to the default types
			guessed from the input table specification.</option>
		<option name="Reset all">Resets all transformations.</option>
		<option name="Enforce types">
				Controls how columns whose type changes are dealt with.
				If selected, we attempt to map to the KNIME type you configured and fail if that's not possible.
				If unselected, the KNIME type corresponding to the new type is used.
		</option>
		<option name="Take columns from">
			Only enabled in several input tables are available. Specifies which set of
			columns are considered for the output table.
			<ul>
				<li>Union: Any column that is part of any input table is considered.
					If an input table is missing a column, it's filled up with missing values.
				</li>
				<li>Intersection: Only columns that appear in all input tables are
					considered for the output table.</li>
			</ul>
			<b>NOTE:</b>
			<p>
			This setting has special implications if you are changing the input table without reconfiguring the node.
			If Intersection is selected any column that moves into the intersection during execution will be considered 
			to be new, even if it was previously part of the union of columns.
			</p>
			<p>
			It is also important to note that the transformation matching during execution is based on name.
			That means if there was a column [A, Integer] during configuration in the
			dialog and this column becomes [A, String] during execution, then the
			stored transformation is applied
			to it. For filtering, ordering and renaming, this is straight forward.
			For type mapping the following is done: If there is an alternative
			converter to the specified KNIME type, then this converter is used,
			otherwise we default to the default KNIME type for the new type. In
			our example we might have specified that [A, Integer] should be
			mapped to Long.
			For the changed column [A, String] there is no converter to Long, so we
			default back to String and A becomes a String column in the output
			table.
			</p>
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table 0">
            Table to manipulate
	    </inPort>
		<dynInPort insert-before="1" name="Table ..." group-identifier="input">
            Table(s) contributing subsequent rows and columns.
		</dynInPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Appended table">
            A table with the transformed columns from all input tables (Table 0, Table 1, Table ...)
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>

