<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="default.png">
	<name>Probability Distribution Creator</name>
	<shortDescription>Creates a Probability Distribution cell out of
		numeric cells.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Creates a column containing a probability distribution either from numeric or string columns. 
			In case of numeric columns, one or more columns that contain probability 
			values can be picked. The probability values must be non-negative and must sum up to 1.
			In case of string columns, one single column can be selected. The probability 
			distribution of the string column produces the same results as applying the numeric probability distribution to 
			the output columns of One to Many node applied to the same string column.
			The node dialog contains three main sections dedicated respectively to numeric columns, string columns
			and common features for both types. 
		</intro>
		<tab name="Numeric Columns">
			<option name="Numeric Column Selection">Move the columns that contain the probability
				values to the "Include" list.
			</option>
			
			<option
				name="Allow probabilities that sum up to 1 imprecisely">If enabled, the probabilities must not sum up to
				1 precisely.
				This might be helpful if there are, e.g., some rounding errors in
				the probability values. A
				number of decimal digits can
				be
				specified
				that defines the
				precision as explained below.
			</option>
			<option name="Precision (number of decimal digits)">
				Defines the precision that the sum of the
				probabilities must have by
				restricting the number of decimal digits that must be precise.
				The
				sum
				is accepted if
				<i>abs(sum - 1) &lt;= 10^(-precision)</i>
				, e.g., if the sum is 0.999, it is only accepted
				with a precision of
				&lt;=2. The lower the specified number, the higher is the tolerance.
			</option>
			
			<option name="Invalid Probability Distribution Handling">
				Specify how to treat invalid probabilities.
				Invalid means, e.g.,
				negative probabilities or probabilities that do
				not sum up to 1 (with
				respect to the specified precision). If
				<i>Fail</i>
				is selected, the node will fail. Otherwise, the node just gives a
				warning and puts missing values in the output for the corresponding
				rows.
			</option>
			
		</tab>
		<tab name="String Columns">
			<option name="String Column Selection">
				A single string column can be picked from the dropdown menu.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="General ">
			<option name="Output column name">
				Specify the name of the created column.
			</option><option name="Remove included columns">If selected, the included numeric columns 
				or the picked string column will be removed
				from the output.
			</option><option name="Missing Value Handling">
				Specify how to treat a missing value in one of the input columns. If
				<i>Fail</i>
				is selected, the node will fail. If
				<i>Ignore</i>
				is selected, the node just gives a warning and puts missing values
				in the output for the corresponding rows.
				If
				<i>Treat as zero</i>
				is selected, the missing value will be treated as 0.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort name="Probability Values" index="0">Data with columns
			containing probability values.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0"
			name="Input Data with Probability Distribution">Input data with an appended column that contains the
			probability
			distribution.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>