<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./refrowsplit.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Reference Row Splitter</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
		Allows rows to be split from the first table using the second table as reference.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node allows you to partition the input table’s rows based on whether a row’s value exists within a set of reference values.
            A row's value is defined by selecting a column to use for comparison.
            The reference set of values is formed from all values in a selected column of the second input table.
            If a row’s value is in the reference set, it is appended to the first output table; otherwise, it is appended to the second output table.
		</intro>
		
        <option name="Data table column">
            The column from the table to be filtered that should be used for comparison.
        </option>
        <option name="Reference table column">
            The column from the filter table that should be used for comparison.
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Table to be split">
            The main table containing rows to be partitioned based on the specified column values.
        </inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Reference table">
            A table that provides the reference set of values used for partitioning, drawn from a selected column.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Table with included rows">
            Contains rows from the input table where the value in the specified column is found within the reference set of values from the reference table.
        </outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Table with excluded rows">
            Contains rows from the input table where the value in the specified column is not found in the reference set from the reference table.
        </outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>