<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./extract_col_header.png" type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>Column Name Extractor</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Creates a new table with a single row or column containing the column names of the input table.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Creates a new table with a single row or column containing the column names.
            The node has two output tables: The first table contains the column headers (all columns are of type string),
            either as a single row containing all headers or as one row per header. The second table contains the
            input data, whereby the column names are changed to a default pattern (given that the corresponding option
            is set.)
        </intro>
        <option name="Generate new column names">
        If selected, the column names of both output tables will be replaced with automatically generated names by
        combining the prefix provided below with the corresponding column number (e.g. "Column 1", "Column 2", and so on).
        Otherwise, the original column names will be used.
        </option>
        <option name="Prefix">Prefix to use when generating new column names</option>
        <option name="Output format for column names">
        	The format in which the first output table provides the extracted column names:
        	<ul>
        		<li><b>Row</b>: The column names are output as a single row with a column per name.</li>
        		<li><b>Column</b>: The column names are output as a single column with a row per name.</li>
        	</ul>
        </option>
        <option name="Restrain column types">
        	Select the type of the columns to extract the names from:
        	<ul>
        		<li><b>All</b>: All columns are processed.</li>
        		<li><b>String</b>: Only string-compatible columns are processed, this includes e.g. XML columns.</li>
        		<li><b>Integer</b>: Only integer-compatible columns are processed.</li>
        		<li><b>Double</b>: Only double-compatible columns are processed. This includes integer and long columns.</li>
        	</ul>
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input data">Original input data</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Column Header Table">Table with single row or column containing original column
            names</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Input table with replaced column header">Input table with either original or changed
            column names</outPort>
    </ports>
    <keywords>
    	<keyword>Column header to row</keyword>
    	<keyword>Column names</keyword>
    </keywords>
</knimeNode>
