<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="csvreader.png" type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>CSV Reader</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Reads CSV files
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		<p>
		  Reads CSV files. Use this node if the workflow is used in a server
		  or batch environment and the input files structure change between
		  different invocations. In particular, this includes a variable number
		  of input columns. Upon execution, the node will scan the input file
		  to determine number and types of the columns and output a table with
		  the auto-guessed structure.  
        </p>
        <p>
          <b>Note:</b> If you find that this node can't read your file, try the <b>File Reader</b> node. It offers more options for reading complex files.
        </p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Settings">
			<option name="Read from">
				Select a file system which stores the data you want to read. There are
				four default file system options to choose from:
				<br />
				<ul>
	                <li><i>Local File System:</i> Allows you to select a file/folder from your
	                    local system.
	                </li>
	                <li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Allows you to read from a mountpoint.
	                	When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to choose the mountpoint.
	                	Unconnected mountpoints are greyed out but can still be selected (note that browsing is disabled in this case).
	                	Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.
	                	A mountpoint is displayed in red if it was previously selected but is no longer available.
	                	You won't be able to save the dialog as long as you don't select a valid i.e. known mountpoint.
	                </li>
	                <li><i>Relative to:</i> Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path
						relative to the current mountpoint, current workflow or the current workflow's data area.
	                When selected a new drop-down menu appears to choose which of the three options to use.
	                </li>
	                <li><i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i> Allows to specify a URL (e.g. file://, http:// or knime:// protocol). 
	                    When selected, a spinner appears that allows you to specify the desired connection and read timeout in milliseconds.
	                    In case it takes longer to connect to the host / read the file, the node fails to execute.
	                    Browsing is disabled for this option.
	                </li>
				</ul>
				To read from other file systems, click on
	            <b>...</b> in the bottom left corner of the node icon followed by
	            <i>Add File System Connection port</i>. Afterwards, connect the desired file system connector
	            node to the newly added input port. The file system connection will then be shown in the drop-down menu.
	            It is greyed out if the file system is not connected in which case you have to (re)execute the connector node first.
				Note: The default file systems listed above can't be selected if a file system is provided via the input port.
			</option>
			<option name="Mode">
				Select whether you want to read a single file or multiple files in a folder.
				When reading files in a folder, you can set filters to specify which
				files and subfolders to include (see below).
			</option>
			<option name="Filter options">
				Only displayed if the mode <i>Files in folder</i> is selected.
				Allows to specify which files should be included according to their file extension and/or name.
				It is also possible to include hidden files.
				The folder filter options enable you to specify which folders should be included based on their name and hidden status.
				Note that the folders themselves will not be included, only the files they contain.
			</option>
			<option name="Include subfolders">
				If this option is checked, the node will include all files from subfolders that satisfy the specified filter options.
				If left unchecked, only the files in the selected folder will be included and all files from subfolders are ignored.
			</option>
			
			
			<option name="File, Folder or URL">
				Enter a URL when reading from <i>Custom/KNIME URL</i>, otherwise enter a path to a file or folder. The
				required syntax of a path depends on the chosen file system, such as &quot;C:\path\to\file&quot; (Local
				File System on Windows) or  &quot;/path/to/file&quot; (Local
	            File System on Linux/MacOS and Mountpoint). For file systems connected via input port, the node
	            description of the respective connector node describes the required path format.
				You can also choose a previously selected file/folder from the drop-down list, or select a location
				from the &quot;Browse...&quot; dialog.
				Note that browsing is disabled in some cases:
				<ul>
					<li><i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i> Browsing is always disabled.</li>
					<li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Browsing is disabled if the selected mountpoint isn't connected.
					Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.</li>
					<li><i>File systems provided via input port:</i>
					Browsing is disabled if the connector node hasn't been executed since the workflow has been opened.
					(Re)execute the connector node to enable browsing.</li>
				</ul>
			</option>	
			<option name="Column delimiter">
			  The character string delimiting columns. Use '\t' for tab character. Can get detected automatically.
			</option>
			<option name="Row delimiter">
	          The character string delimiting rows. Use '\n' for new line character. Can get detected automatically.
			</option>
			<option name="Quote char">
	          The quote character. Can get detected automatically. 
			</option>			
			<option name="Quote escape char">
	          The character is used for escaping quotes inside an already quoted value. Can get detected automatically.
			</option>
			<option name="Autodetect format">
	          By pressing this button, the "Column delimiter", "Row delimiter", "Quote char" and "Quote escape char" get 
	          automatically detected, though it is not guaranteed that the correct values are being detected.<br/>
	          Only a single file is considered for auto-detection, i.e., if "Files in folder" is selected only the first
	          file is being used.
	          The auto-detection by default is based on the first 1024 * 1024 characters of the selected file, but
	          can be adjusted by clicking the settings button next to this option.
	          The format can only be detected if the read number of characters comprises one full data row and the 
	          auto-detection will take at most 20 data rows into account. It is assumed that data rows are separated by
	          line breaks. Note that the "Skip first lines" option as well as the specified  "Comment char" will be used
	          when guessing the file's format.
			</option>
			<option name="Comment char">
	          A character indicating line comments.
			</option>
			<option name="Has column header">
	          Select this box if the first row contains column name headers.  
			</option>
			<option name="Has row ID">
	          Select this box if the first column contains row IDs
	          (no duplicates allowed).  
			</option>
			<option name="Prepend file index to row ID">
			  Select this box if you want to prepend a prefix that depends on the index of the source file to the row IDs.
			  The prefix for the first file is "File_0_", for the second "File_1_" and so on.
			  This option is useful if the row IDs within a single file are unique but the same row IDs appear in multiple files.
			</option>
			<option name="Support short data rows">
	          Select this box if some rows may be shorter than others (filled with missing values).
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Transformation">
			<option name="Transformations">
				This tab displays every column as a row in a table that allows modifying the structure of the output table.
				It supports reordering, filtering and renaming columns. It is also possible to change the type of the columns.
				Reordering is done via drag-and-drop. Just drag a column to the position it should have in the output table.
				Whether and where to add unknown columns during execution is specified via the special row &lt;any unknown new column&gt;.
				Note that the positions of columns are reset in the dialog if a new file or folder is selected.
			</option>
			<option name="Reset order">Resets the order of columns to the order in the input file/folder.</option>
			<option name="Reset filter">Clicking this button will reset the filters i.e. all columns will be included.</option>
			<option name="Reset names">Resets the names to the names that are read from file or created if the file/folder doesn't contain column names.</option>
			<option name="Reset types">Resets the output types to the default types guessed from the input file/folder.</option>
			<option name="Reset all">Resets all transformations.</option>
			<option name="Enforce types">
				Controls how columns whose type changes are dealt with. If selected, we attempt to map to the KNIME type you
				configured and fail if that's not possible.
				If unselected, the KNIME type corresponding to the new type is used.
			</option>
			<option name="Take columns from">Only enabled in "Files in folder" mode. Specifies which set of columns are considered for the output table.
				<ul>
					<li>Union: Any column that is part of any input file is considered. If a file is missing a column, it's filled up with missing values.</li>
					<li>Intersection: Only columns that appear in all files are considered for the output table.</li>
				</ul>
				<b>NOTE:</b> This setting has special implications if you are controlling the input location with a flow variable. 
				If Intersection is selected any column that moves into the intersection during execution will be considered to be new, even if it was previously part of the union of columns.
				It is also important to note that the transformation matching during execution is based on name.
				That means if there was a column [A, Integer] during configuration in the dialog and this column becomes [A, String] during execution, then the stored transformation is applied
				to it. For filtering, ordering and renaming, this is straight forward. For type mapping the following is done: If there is an alternative converter to the specified KNIME type, then this converter is used,
				otherwise we default to the default KNIME type for the new type. In our example we might have specified that [A, Integer] should be mapped to Long.
				For the changed column [A, String] there is no converter to Long, so we default back to String and A becomes a String column in the output table.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Advanced Settings">
			<option name="Limit memory per column">
				If selected the memory per column is restricted to 1MB in order to prevent memory exhaustion. Uncheck
				this option to disable these memory restrictions.
			</option>
			<option name="Maximum number of columns">
				Sets the number of allowed columns (default 8192 columns) to
				prevent memory exhaustion. The node will fail if the number of columns
				exceeds the set limit.
			</option>
			<option name="Quote options">
				<ul>
					<li>Remove quotes and trim whitespaces: Quotes will be removed from the value followed by trimming
					any leading/trailing whitespaces.</li>
					<li>Keep quotes: The quotes of a value will be kept. Note: No trimming will be done inside the quotes.</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
			<option name="Replace empty quoted strings with missing values">
				Select this box if you want <b>quoted</b> empty strings to be replaced by missing value cells.
			</option>
			<option name="Table specification">
			  If enabled, only the specified number of input <i>rows</i> are used to analyze the file (i.e to determine
	          the column types). This option is recommended for long files where the first <i>n</i> rows are 
	          representative for the whole file. The "Skip first data rows"
	          option has no effect on the scanning. Note also, that this option and the "Limit data rows" option are 
	          independent from each other, i.e., if the value in "Limit data rows" is smaller than the value specified
	          here, we will still read as many rows as specified here.
			</option>
			<option name="Support changing file schemas">
			  If selected, the reader will compute the table specification on execution.
			  This behavior is required if the content of the configured file/folder changes between executions, 
			  i.e., columns are added/removed to/from file(s) or their types change.
			  NOTE: When checked, the node will not output a table specification during configure and won't apply transformations
			  (therefore the transformation tab is disabled).
			</option>
			<option name="Number format">
			  Allows to specify the thousands and decimal separator character for parsing numbers.
			  The thousands separator is used for integer, long and double parsing, while the decimal separator is only used for the parsing of double values.
			  Note that the two must differ.
			  While it is possible to leave the thousands separator unspecified, you must always provide a decimal separator.
			</option>
			<option name="Fail on differing specs">
				If checked, the node will fail if multiple files are read via the Files in folder option and not all files have the same table structure i.e. the same columns.
			</option>	
		</tab>
	    <tab name="Limit Rows">
			<option name="Skip first lines">
	          If enabled, the specified number of lines are skipped in the input file before the parsing starts. 
	          Use this option to skip lines that do not fit in the table structure (e.g. multi-line comments) 
			</option>
			<option name="Skip first data rows">
	          If enabled, the specified number of valid data rows are skipped. This has no effect on which row will be 
	          chosen as a column header.
			</option>
			<option name="Limit data rows">
	          If enabled, only the specified number of data rows are read. The column header row (if selected) is 
	          not taken into account.    
			</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Encoding">
	        <option name="Encoding">
	            To read a CSV file that contains characters in a different encoding, you can select the character set in this tab (UTF-8, 
	            UTF-16, etc.), or specify any other encoding supported by your Java VM. The default value uses the default
	            encoding of the Java VM, which may depend on the locale or the Java property &quot;file.encoding&quot;
	        </option>
        </tab>	
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0" name="File system connection"
			group-identifier="File System Connection">
			The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="File Table">
		  File being read with number and types of columns guessed automatically.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>   
        
        
        
        