<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="stringtopath.png" type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1
	http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>String to Path</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Converts a string column into a path column.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>This node converts a string column into a
			<a href="https://docs.knime.com/2021-06/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#path">path
            column.</a>
            </p>

            <p>
            <i>This node can access a variety of different</i>
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/2021-06/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#analytics-platform-file-systems"><i>file systems.</i></a> 
            <i>More information about file handling in KNIME can be found in the official</i> 
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html"><i>File Handling Guide.</i></a>
            </p>

		</intro>
		<option name="File system">
			Select the file system to which the created paths should be related to. There are four default file system
			options to choose from:
			<br />
			<ul>
				<li>
					<i>Local File System:</i>
					Resolve the path to your local file system.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Mountpoint:</i>
					Resolves the path to a mountpoint. When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to choose the
					mountpoint. Unconnected mountpoints are grayed out but can still be selected. A mountpoint is 
					displayed in red if it was previously selected but is no longer available. You won't be able to save
					the dialog as long as you don't select a valid i.e. known mountpoint.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Relative to:</i>
					Resolve the path relative to the current mountpoint, current workflow or the current workflow's data
					area. When selected a new drop-down menu appears to choose which of the three options to use.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i>
					Resolve the paths to a URL (e.g. file://, http:// or knime:// protocol). When selected, a spinner
					appears that allows you to specify the desired connection and write timeout in milliseconds..
				</li>
			</ul>
			It is possible to use other file systems with this node. Therefore, you have to enable the file system
			connection input port of this node by clicking the <b>...</b> in the bottom left corner of the node's icon
			and choose <i>Add File System Connection port</i>.
			<br />
			Afterwards, you can simply connect the desired connector node to this node. The file system connection will
			then be shown in the drop-down menu. It is grayed out if the file system is not connected in which case you
			have to (re)execute the connector node first.
			Note: The default file systems listed above can't be selected if a file system is provided via the input
			port.
		</option>
		<option name="Column selection">
			Column that will be converted. It has to contain a string with correct Path /foo/bar.txt syntax.
		</option>
		<option name="Fail if file/folder does not exist">
			Checks if the files or folders referenced by the created Paths are existing and will abort if one is not.
		</option>
		<option name="Fail on missing values">
			If selected the node will fail if the selected column contains missing values.
		</option>
		<option name="Output">
			<ul>
				<li>
					<b>Append column:</b> Append the new column to the table with the selected column name.
				</li>
				<li>
					<b>Replace:</b> Replace the selected column with the new Path column.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</option>
		<option name="New column name">
			Name of the appended column.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input table">Table that contains a String column with
			path information.
		</inPort>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0" name="File system connection"
			group-identifier="File System Connection">
			The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<outPort name="Output table" index="0">
			Input table with the
			corresponding Path column to the selected column. It will either be
			appended or replacing the old column, depending on the configuration.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
