<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./duplicate_filter.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Duplicate Filter</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Removes or marks duplicate rows.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		This node identifies duplicate rows. Duplicate rows have
        identical values in certain columns. The node chooses a single 
        row for each set of duplicates ("chosen"). You can either remove all duplicate
        rows from the input table and keep only unique rows and chosen rows or
        mark the rows with additional information about their duplication status.
		</intro>
	<tab name="Options">
		<option name="Choose columns for duplicates detection">
            Allows to select those columns that identify the duplicates. Columns
            not selected are handled under "Row selection" in the "Advanced" tab.
		</option>
	</tab>
	<tab name="Advanced - Duplicate Rows">
		<option name="Remove duplicates">
            Removes duplicate rows and keeps only unique and chosen rows.
		</option>
		<option name="Keep duplicate rows">
			Appends columns with additional information to the input table:
			<ul>
				<li><b>Add classification column</b>: Appends a column that describes
					the type of row:
					<ul>
						<li><i>unique</i>: There is no other row with the same 
							values in the selected columns.
						</li>
						<li><i>chosen</i>: This row was chosen from a set of duplicate
                            rows.
						</li>
						<li><i>duplicate</i>: This row is a duplicate and represented by
							another row.
						</li>
					</ul>
				</li>
				<li><b>Add ROWID column</b>: Appends a column with the
                    ROWID of the chosen row for duplicate rows. Unique and chosen rows
                    will not have a ROWID assigned.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</option>
	</tab>
	<tab name="Advanced - Row selection">
		<option name="Select row:">
			Defines which row for each set of duplicates is selected:
			<ul>
				<li><b>First</b>:The first row in sequence is chosen.
				</li>
				<li><b>Last</b>:The last row in sequence is chosen.
				</li>
                <li><b>Minimum of</b>:The <i>first</i> row with the lowest value in
                    the selected column is chosen. Missing values are sorted after the highest value.
				</li>
				<li><b>Maximum of</b>:The <i>first</i> row with the largest value in
					the selected column is chosen. Missing values are sorted before the lowest value.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</option>
	</tab>
    <tab name="Advanced - Additional options">
		<option name="In-memory computation">
            If selected, computation is speed up by utilizing working memory (RAM). The amount
            of required memory is higher than for a regular computation and also depends
            on the amount of input data.
		</option>
		<option name="Retain row order">
            If selected, rows in the output table are sorted in the same order as in the input
            table.
		</option>
    </tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort name="Input Data" index="0">
			The data table containing potential duplicates.
		</inPort>
		<outPort name="Filtered/Labeled Data" index="0">
			Either the input data without duplicates or the input data with additional
			columns identifying duplicates.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>