<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="./duplicate_row_filter.png" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Duplicate Row Filter</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Removes or marks duplicate rows.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		This node identifies duplicate rows. Duplicate rows have
        identical values in certain columns. The node chooses a single 
        row for each set of duplicates ("chosen"). You can either remove all duplicate
        rows from the input table and keep only unique and chosen rows or
        mark the rows with additional information about their duplication status.
		</intro>
	<tab name="Options">
		<option name="Choose columns for duplicates detection">
            Allows the selection of columns identifying the duplicates. Columns
            not selected are handled under "Row selection" in the "Advanced" tab.
		</option>
	</tab>
	<tab name="Duplicate Rows">
		<option name="Remove duplicates">
            Advanced setting that removes duplicate rows and keeps only unique and chosen rows.
		</option>
		<option name="Keep duplicate rows">
			Advanced setting that appends columns with additional information to the input table:
			<ul>
				<li><b>Add column showing the row status ('unique', 'chosen', 'duplicate') to all rows</b>: 
				Appends a column with the row status:
						<br/><i>unique</i>: There is no other row with the same 
							values in the selected columns.
						<br/><i>chosen</i>: This row was chosen from a set of duplicate
                            rows.
						<br/><i>duplicate</i>: This row is a duplicate and represented by
							another row.
				</li>
				<li><b>Add column identifying the RowID</b>: Appends a column with the
                    RowID of the chosen row for duplicate rows. Unique and chosen rows
                    will not have a RowID assigned.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</option>
		<option name="Row chosen in case of duplicate">
			Advanced setting that defines which row for each set of duplicates is selected:
			<ul>
				<li><b>First</b>:The first row in sequence is chosen.
				</li>
				<li><b>Last</b>:The last row in sequence is chosen.
				</li>
                <li><b>Minimum of</b>:The <i>first</i> row with the minimum value in the selected 
                	column is chosen. In case of strings, the row will be chosen following lexicographical
                	order. Missing values are sorted after the maximum value.
				</li>
				<li><b>Maximum of</b>:The <i>first</i> row with the maximum value in the selected 
                	column is chosen. In case of strings, the row will be chosen following lexicographical
                	order. Missing values are sorted before the minimum value.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</option>
	</tab>
    <tab name="Additional options">
		<option name="In-memory computation">
            Advanced setting that, if selected, speeds up computation by utilizing working memory (RAM). The amount
            of required memory is higher than for a regular computation and also depends
            on the amount of input data.
		</option>
		<option name="Retain row order">
            Advanced setting that, if selected, ensures that the rows in the output table are in the same order as in the
             input table.
		</option>
		<option name="Update domains of all columns">
            Advanced setting to enable recomputation of the domain of all columns in the output table such that the 
            domain's bounds exactly match the bounds of the data in the output table.
		</option>
    </tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort name="Input Data" index="0">
			The data table containing potential duplicates.
		</inPort>
		<outPort name="Filtered/Labeled Data" index="0">
			Either the input data without duplicates or the input data with additional
			columns identifying duplicates.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>