<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./linereader.png" type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Line Reader</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Read lines from a file or URL.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Read lines from a file or URL. Each line will be represented by a
			single string data cell in a single row. The row prefix and column header 
			can be specified in the dialog.
		</intro>
		<option name="File or files in folder">
			Select whether you want to read a file or multiple files within a folder.
		</option>
		<option name="Read from..."> 
			Select a file system which stores the data you want to read. There are four default file system options to choose from:<br/>
			<ul>
				<li>Local File System: Allows you to select a file/folder from your local system.</li>
				<li>Relative to: Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path relative to the workflow, mountpoint or node.</li>
				<li>Mountpoint: Allows you to choose a mountpoint. Whenever this is selected, a new drop-down menu appears to choose from available mountpoints.</li>
				<li>Custom URL: Uses the standard URL handler providing the ability to read a file from URLs (e.g. file, http or KNIME protocol). Browsing and reading folders are disabled for this option.</li>
			</ul>
			It is possible to use other file systems with this node. Therefore, you have to enable the file system connection input port of this node by clicking the <b>...</b> in the bottom left corner of the node's icon and choose <i>Add File System Connection port</i>.<br/>
			Afterwards, you can simply connect the desired connector node to the reader node. The file system connection will then be shown in the drop down menu.
		</option>	
		<option name="File/folder or URL">
			Enter a valid destination. Depending on the selected file system this is either a path (used by <i>Local File System</i>, <i>Relative to</i>, <i>Mountpoint</i> options and custom file systems added by specific connector nodes) or a URL (used by <i>Custom URL</i> option).<br/>
			A path usually starts with a slash (/) character and does not contain a protocol.
			You can also choose a previously selected file/folder from the drop-down list, or select a destination from	the &quot;Browse...&quot; dialog (browsing is not available for custom URLs).
		</option>
		<option name="Include subfolders">
			Check if you want to include all matching files from subfolders of the defined location.
		</option>
		<option name="Filter options">
			Press this button for file filtering options.
		</option>
		<option name="File filtering: File extension(s)">
			Enter file extensions used to filter files.
			Additionally, there is an option to choose whether the filter should work in a case sensitive or insensitive manner. <br/>
			<i>Note</i>: A file extension has to be entered without the preceding dot. Multiple extensions have to be separated by a semicolon character (e.g. <i>txt;log</i>). 
		</option>
		<option name="File filtering: File names">
			Select the desired filter method (regular expression or wildcard) and enter a valid expression to match the filenames of the files to be read.
			Additionally, there is an option to choose whether the filter should work in a case sensitive or insensitive manner.
		</option>
		<option name="File filtering options: Filter hidden files">
			Select if hidden files should be filtered.
		</option>
		<option name="Row header prefix">
			The prefix of the row headers (amended by a running index).
		</option>
		<option name="Column header">
			The name of the single output column.
		</option>
		<option name="Use first line as column header">
            If selected, the first line in the file will be used as column header. If it is used together with 
            the "Limit number of rows" option it does not count as row.
  		</option>
		<option name="Skip empty lines">
			If set, empty lines are skipped. This also includes lines only containing
			white space characters such as spaces or tabs.
		</option>
		<option name="Limit number of rows">
			If set, the node will not read more lines than specified. If "Skip empty rows"
			is selected, empty rows do not count as valid rows.  
		</option>
		<option name="Match input against regex">
		    If set, lines that do not match the specified regular expression are skipped.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0" name="File system connection" group-identifier="File System Connection"> 
			The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Lines from the file(s)">The lines as read from the
			file(s), each line represented by a single cell in a data row.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
