<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="create_temp_dir.png" type="Other"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Create Temp Folder</name>
	<shortDescription>Creates a temporary folder upon execute and exposes its path as flow variable.      </shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
            <p><i>This node supports the 
            </i><a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#path"><i>path flow variable</i></a>
            <i> to specify the base location. To convert the created path variables to string variables which are 
            required by some nodes that have not been migrated yet you can use the </i>
            <a href="https://kni.me/n/7iP1GCKnb_WMgJ4V"><i>Path to String (Variable)</i></a><i> node.</i>
            <i> For further information about file handling in general see the 
            </i><a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html"><i>File Handling Guide.</i></a><br/></p>
            
            <p>
		    Creates a temporary folder upon execute and exposes its path
			as flow variable. This can be useful in (a) demo applications where
			the actual path of the output is not all that relevant, e.g. the
			KNIME public workflow server and (b) KNIME WebPortal and quickform
			flows, where some data is written, which is later downloaded by means
			of, e.g. a web link. The folder is deleted upon closing the
			workflow. The node can be also configured in a way that the created
			temporary folder is deleted upon reset.
			<br/>
			<i>Note:</i> By default the temporary folder is created directly in the workflow data area,
			as defined by “.“ in the Folder field
			</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Write to">
				Select a file system in which you want to create the temporary folder.
				There are three default file system options to choose from:
				<br />
				<ul>
					<li><i>Local File System:</i> Allows you to select a folder on your
	                    local system.
	                </li>
	                <li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Allows you to read from a mountpoint.
	                	When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to choose the mountpoint.
	                	Unconnected mountpoints are greyed out but can still be selected (note that browsing is disabled in this case).
	                	Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.
	                	A mountpoint is displayed in red if it was previously selected but is no longer available.
	                	You won't be able to save the dialog as long as you don't select a valid i.e. known mountpoint.
	                </li>
	                <li><i>Relative to:</i> Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path
						relative to the current mountpoint, current workflow or the current workflow's data area.
	                When selected a new drop-down menu appears to choose which of the three options to use.
	                </li>
				</ul>
				It is possible to use other file systems with this node. Therefore,
				you have to enable the file system connection input port of this
				node
				by clicking the
				<b>...</b>
				in the bottom left corner of the node's icon and choose
				<i>Add File System Connection port</i>
				.
				<br />
				Afterwards, you can simply connect the desired connector node to this node.
				The file system connection will then be shown in the drop-down menu.
				It is greyed out if the file system is not connected in which case you have to (re)execute the connector node first.
				Note: The default file systems listed above can't be selected if a file system is provided via the input port.
			</option>
		<option name="Folder">
			Enter a valid location where the temporary folder
			will be created at. The
				required syntax of a path depends on the chosen file system, such as &quot;C:\path\to\file&quot; (Local
				File System on Windows) or  &quot;/path/to/file&quot; (Local
	            File System on Linux/MacOS and Mountpoint). For file systems connected via input port, the node
	            description of the respective connector node describes the required path format.
				You can also choose a previously selected folder from the drop-down list, or select a location
				from the &quot;Browse...&quot; dialog.
				Note that browsing is disabled in some cases:
				<ul>
					<li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Browsing is disabled if the selected mountpoint isn't connected.
					Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.</li>
					<li><i>File systems provided via input port:</i>
					Browsing is disabled if the connector node hasn't been executed since the workflow has been opened.
					(Re)execute the connector node to enable browsing.</li>
				</ul>
                <i>The location can be exposed as or automatically set via a 
                </i><a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#path">
                <i>path flow variable.</i></a>
		</option>
		<option name="Create missing folders">Select if the folders of the selected output
			location should be created if they do not already exist. If this
			option is unchecked, the node will fail if a folder does not
			exist.
		</option>
		<option name="Delete temp folder on reset">Check this box to delete the folder and all its
			content when the node is reset.
		</option>
		<option name="Temp folder prefix">Name prefix of the temporary folder. It will be
			amended by some random number to ensure uniqueness.
		</option>
		<option name="Export path as (variable name)">The name of the exported variable denoting the
			actual path of the created temporary folder.
		</option>
		<option name="Additional path variables">A list of additional variables that will be
			created by the node. Each variable will denote a path to a file or folder.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort name="Input variables (optional)" index="0">
			Input variables (optional).
		</inPort>
		<dynInPort group-identifier="File System Connection"
			insert-before="0" name="File system connection">The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Flow Variables with path information">Flow Variables with path information.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>