<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="diagnoseworkflow.svg" type="Source">
	<name>Diagnose Workflow</name>
	<shortDescription>Gathers information on the workflow the node is
		placed in.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				This node outputs a table that contains basic information about every
				node in the workflow, like the name, ID, size on disk and execution
				time.
			</p>
			<p>
				The output table lists all nodes in the workflow that were executed
				since the last reset. This
				also includes nodes in metanodes up to the specified nesting depth. The
				detailed statistics are:
				<ul>
					<li>Row Key: The row key corresponds to the unique node ID</li>
					<li>Name: Name of the node</li>
					<li>Class Name: If available, the class name of the node factory</li>
					<li>Type: Either Native Node, Metanode or Component</li>
					<li>Source URI: If available (i.e. the node is a linked
						Metanode/Component), the location of the source node</li>
					<li>Deprecated: Whether the node is marked as deprecated</li>
					<li>Disk Space: The size of the node on disk, including
						configuration, data and potential sub-workflows</li>
					<li>Execution Time: How long the last execution of the node took in
						milliseconds</li>
					<li>Nr of Executions: How often the node has been executed since
						the start of the application</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				Additionally, this node outputs a workflow summary string in XML or JSON format
				that includes even more useful information like the configuration
				settings of the node or its ports.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Include component contents">Whether to include the nodes inside a component</option>
		<option name="Output format">Whether the WorkflowSummary shall be in JSON or
			XML format</option>
		<option name="Include properties">What properties to include in the node overview</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="Node Overview">Listing of all nodes in the workflow,
			enhanced by some simple statistics</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Workflow Summary">The generated workflow summary</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>