<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./file_system_connector.png"
	type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">

    <name>KNIME Mountpoint Connector</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Provides a file system connection with access to a KNIME Mountpoint, for example "LOCAL", or "My-KNIME-Hub".
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
         <intro>
            <p>Provides a file system connection with access to a KNIME Mountpoint, for example "LOCAL", or "My-KNIME-Hub".
            It can also provide a file system connection with access to the mountpoint which contains the current workflow.
            The resulting output port allows downstream nodes to access <i>files</i>, e.g. to read or write, or to perform other file system operations
            (browse/list files, copy, move, ...) in the selected mountpoint.
            </p>
            
            <p><b>Note:</b>In many cases it is not necessary to use this connector node. Nodes that require
            file system access (e.g. the File Reader node) already provide the same level of access, by choosing for example 
            <i>Read from</i> > <i>Mountpoint.</i> The purpose of this connector node is to make file access with
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#path-syntax">relative paths</a>
            more flexible, by allowing to explicitly configure the 
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#working-directory">working
            directory</a> of the resulting file system connection. For example,
            this makes it easier to relocate (or change) the files that your workflow accesses, because you only need to change
            the working directory.
            </p>
            
            <p><b>Path syntax:</b> Paths for this connector are specified with a UNIX-like syntax such as /myfolder/myfile. An absolute
            path consists of:
                <ol>
                    <li>A leading slash ("/").</li>
                    <li>Followed by the path to the file ("myfolder/myfile" in the above example).</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            
        </intro>
        <tab name="Settings">
            <option name="Mountpoint selection">
                Specify the <i>mountpoint</i> to access.
                
                <ul>
                <li>
                <b>Current mountpoint:</b> If chosen, the file system connection will give access to the mountpoint which contains the <i>current workflow.</i> If you
                are not using this connector node, this option is equivalent to choosing <i>Read from</i> > <i>Relative to</i> > <i>Current mountpoint.</i>
                Selecting the option <b>Set working directory to the current workflow,</b> will additionally set the working directory of the file system
                connection to the location of the current workflow. This is then equivalent to choosing <i>Read from</i> > <i>Relative to</i> > <i>Current workflow.</i>
                </li>

                <li>
                <b>Other mountpoint:</b> If chosen, the file system connection will give access to the selected mountpoint. Unconnected mountpoints are greyed out 
                and can still be selected, but you need to go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint before executing this node. A mountpoint is
                displayed in red if it was previously selected but is no longer available. You will not be able to save the dialog in this case.
                </li>
                </ul> 
                
            </option>

	        <option name="Working directory">
		        Specify the <i>working directory</i> of the resulting file system connection, using the <b>Path syntax</b> explained above. The working
		        directory must be specified as an absolute path. A working directory allows downstream nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i>
		        paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading slash. The default working directory is "/".
		    </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="File System Connection">
             File system connection to the current mountpoint, or the selected mountpoint.
        </outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
