<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="tableread.png" type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Table Reader</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Reads table written by the Table Writer node.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				This node reads files that have been written using the Table
				Writer node
				(which uses an internal format). It retains all meta
				information
				such as
				domain, properties, colors, size.
			</p>

            <p>
            <i>This node can access a variety of different</i>
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/2021-06/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#analytics-platform-file-systems"><i>file systems.</i></a> 
            <i>More information about file handling in KNIME can be found in the official</i> 
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html"><i>File Handling Guide.</i></a>
            </p>

		</intro>
		<tab name="Settings">
			<option name="Read from">
				Select a file system which stores the data you want to read. There
				are
				four default file system options to choose from:
				<br />
				<ul>
					<li>
						<i>Local File System:</i>
						Allows you to select a file/folder from your
						local system.
					</li>
					<li>
						<i>Mountpoint:</i>
						Allows you to read from a mountpoint.
						When selected, a new
						drop-down menu appears to choose the mountpoint.
						Unconnected
						mountpoints are greyed out but can still be selected
						(note that
						browsing is disabled in this case).
						Go to the KNIME Explorer and
						connect to the mountpoint to enable
						browsing.
						A mountpoint is
						displayed in red if it was previously selected but
						is no longer
						available.
						You won't be able to save the dialog as long as you
						don't select a
						valid i.e. known mountpoint.
					</li>
					<li>
						<i>Relative to:</i>
						Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path
						relative to the
						current mountpoint, current workflow or the current workflow's
						data area.
						When selected a new drop-down menu appears to choose
						which of the
						three options to use.
					</li>
					<li>
						<i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i>
						Allows to specify a URL (e.g. file://, http:// or knime://
						protocol).
						When selected, a spinner appears that allows you to
						specify the
						desired connection and read timeout in milliseconds.
						In
						case it takes longer to connect to the host / read the file, the
						node fails to execute.
						Browsing is disabled for this option.
					</li>
				</ul>
				To read from other file systems, click on
				<b>...</b>
				in the bottom left corner of the node icon followed by
				<i>Add File System Connection port</i>
				. Afterwards, connect the desired file system connector
				node to the
				newly added input port. The file system connection will then
				be shown
				in the drop-down menu.
				It is greyed out if the file system is not
				connected in which case you
				have to (re)execute the connector node
				first.
				Note: The default file
				systems listed above can't be selected
				if a file system is provided
				via the input port.
			</option>
			<option name="Mode">
				Select whether you want to read a single file or
				multiple files in a folder.
				When reading files in a folder, you can
				set filters to specify which
				files and subfolders to include (see
				below).
			</option>
			<option name="Filter options">
				Only displayed if the mode
				<i>Files in folder</i>
				is selected.
				Allows to specify which files should be included
				according to their file extension and/or name.
				It is also possible to
				include hidden files.
				The folder filter options enable you to specify
				which folders should be included based on their name and hidden
				status.
				Note that the folders themselves will not be included, only
				the files they contain.
			</option>
			<option name="Include subfolders">
				If this option is checked, the node will include
				all files from subfolders that satisfy the specified filter options.
				If left unchecked, only the files in the selected folder will be
				included and all files from subfolders are ignored.
			</option>


			<option name="File, Folder or URL">
				Enter a URL when reading from
				<i>Custom/KNIME URL</i>,
				otherwise enter a path to a file or folder. The
				required syntax of a
				path depends on the chosen file system, such as
				&quot;C:\path\to\file&quot; (Local
				File System on Windows) or
				&quot;/path/to/file&quot; (Local
				File System on Linux/MacOS and
				Mountpoint). For file systems connected
				via input port, the node
				description of the respective connector node describes the required
				path
				format.
				You can also choose a previously selected file/folder
				from
				the drop-down list, or select a location
				from the
				&quot;Browse...&quot; dialog.
				Note that browsing is disabled in some
				cases:
				<ul>
					<li>
						<i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i>
						Browsing is always disabled.
					</li>
					<li>
						<i>Mountpoint:</i>
						Browsing is disabled if the selected mountpoint isn't connected.
						Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable
						browsing.
					</li>
					<li>
						<i>File systems provided via input port:</i>
						Browsing is disabled if the connector node hasn't been executed
						since the workflow has been opened.
						(Re)execute the connector node
						to enable browsing.
					</li>
				</ul>
				<i>The location can be exposed as or automatically set via a
				</i>
				<a
					href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#path">
					<i>path flow variable.</i>
				</a>
			</option>
			<option name="Use existing RowID">
				Check this box if the RowIDs from the input tables should be used for
				the
				output tables. If unchecked, a new RowID is generated.
				The generated RowID follows the schema "Row0", "Row1" and so on.
			</option>
			<option name="Prepend table index to RowID">
				Only enabled if the existing RowIDs are used. If checked, a prefix is
				prepended to the RowIDs that indicates which table the row came
				from.
				The format of the prefix is "File_0_", "File_1_" and so on.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Transformation">
			<option name="Transformations">
				This tab displays every column as a row in a
				table that allows modifying
				the structure of the output table.
				It
				supports reordering, filtering and renaming columns. It is also
				possible to change the type of the columns.
				Reordering is done via
				drag-and-drop. Just drag a column to the position it
				should have in
				the output table.
				Whether and where to add unknown columns during
				execution is specified via
				the special row &lt;any unknown new
				column&gt;.
				Note that the positions of columns are reset in the
				dialog if a new file
				or folder is selected.
			</option>
			<option name="Reset order">Resets the order of columns to the order in the
				input file/folder.
			</option>
			<option name="Reset filter">Clicking this button will reset the filters i.e.
				all columns will be included.
			</option>
			<option name="Reset names">Resets the names to the names that are read from
				file or created if the file/folder doesn't contain column names.
			</option>
			<option name="Reset types">Resets the output types to the default types
				guessed from the input file/folder.
			</option>
			<option name="Reset all">Resets all transformations.</option>
			<option name="Enforce types">
				Controls how columns whose type changes are dealt
				with. If selected, we
				attempt to map to the KNIME type you
				configured
				and fail if that's not possible.
				If unselected, the KNIME type
				corresponding to the new type is used.
			</option>
			<option name="Take columns from">
				Only enabled in "Files in folder" mode. Specifies which set of
				columns are considered for the output table.
				<ul>
					<li>Union: Any column that is part of any input file is considered.
						If a file is missing a column, it's filled up with missing values.
					</li>
					<li>Intersection: Only columns that appear in all files are
						considered for the output table.
					</li>
				</ul>
				<b>NOTE:</b>
				This setting has special implications if you are controlling the
				input location with a flow variable.
				If Intersection is selected any
				column that moves into the
				intersection during execution will be
				considered to be new, even if
				it was previously part of the union of
				columns.
				It is also important to note that the transformation
				matching during
				execution is based on name.
				That means if there was a
				column [A, Integer] during configuration in
				the dialog and this
				column becomes [A, String] during execution,
				then the stored
				transformation is applied
				to it. For filtering, ordering and
				renaming, this is straight forward.
				For type mapping the following is
				done: If there is an alternative
				converter to the specified KNIME
				type, then this converter is used,
				otherwise we default to the
				default KNIME type for the new type. In
				our example we might have
				specified that [A, Integer] should be
				mapped to Long.
				For the changed
				column [A, String] there is no converter to Long, so we
				default back
				to String and A becomes a String column in the output
				table.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Advanced Settings">
			<option name="Skip first data rows">
				If enabled, the specified number of valid data
				rows are skipped.
			</option>
			<option name="Limit data rows">
				If enabled, only the specified number of data
				rows are read.
			</option>
			<option name="When schema in file has changed">
				Allows to specify the node behavior if the content of the configured file/folder
				changes between executions, i.e., columns are added/removed to/from the file(s)
				or their types change. The following options are available:
				<ul>
				<li><b>Fail:</b> If set, the node fails if the data schema in the file has changed.</li>
				<li><b>Ignore:</b> If set, the node tries to ignore the changes and outputs a table with the old table specification.
				This is not recommended, as it may lead to invalid data in the resulting table. The "Use new schema" option should be used
				instead.
				</li>
				<li><b>Use new schema:</b> If set, the node will compute a new table specification for the current
				schema of the file at the time when the node is executed. Note that the node will not output a table specification
				before execution and that it will not apply transformations, therefore the transformation tab is disabled.
				</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
			<option name="Fail if specs differ">
				If checked, the node will fail if multiple files
				are read via the Files in folder option and not all files have the
				same table structure i.e. the same columns.
			</option>
			<option name="Path column">
			    If checked, the node will append a path column with the provided name to the output table.
			    This column contains for each row which file it was read from.
			    The node will fail if adding the column with the provided name causes a name collision with any of the columns in the read table.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0" name="File system connection"
			group-identifier="File System Connection">
			The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<outPort name="Read table" index="0">The table contained in the
			selected file.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
