<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="collectioncreate.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.6" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.6 http://knime.org/node/v3.6.xsd">
    <name>Create Collection Column</name>
    <shortDescription>
        Combines multiple columns into a new collection column.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node aggregates multiple columns in a separate new column, whose
            type is a "collection type". The cells in the new column are typed
            collections of cells; that is, the content can be safely be split into
            the original column content. The reverse operation is available 
            in the "Split Collection Column" node. 
        </intro>

        <tab name="Manual Selection">
            <option name="Include">
                This list contains the names of the columns in the input table
                that are included in the output table.
            </option>

            <option name="Exclude">
                This list contains the names of the columns in the input table
                that are excluded from the output table.
            </option>

            <option name="Filter">
                Use one of these fields to filter either the Include or Exclude
                list for certain column names or name substrings.
            </option>

            <option name="Buttons">
                Use these buttons to move columns between the Include and Exclude 
                list. Single-arrow buttons will move all selected columns.
                Double-arrow buttons will move all columns (filtering is taken into
                account).
            </option>

            <option name="Enforce Exclusion">
                Select this option to enforce the current exclusion list to stay
                the same even if the input table specification changes. If some
                of the excluded columns are not available anymore, a warning
                is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the 
                inclusion list.)
            </option>

            <option name="Enforce Inclusion">
                Select this option to enforce the current inclusion list to stay
                the same even if the input table specification changes. If some
                of the included columns are not available anymore, a warning
                is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
                exclusion list.)
            </option>
        </tab>

        <tab name="Wildcard/Regex Selection">
            <option name="">
                Type a search pattern which matches columns to move into the
                Include list. You can use either Wildcards ('?' matching any
                        character, '*' matching a sequence of any characters) or Regex.
                You can specify if your pattern should be case sensitive.
            </option>
        </tab>

        <tab name="Type selection">
            <option name="">
                Select the column types that you want to include. Column types
                that are currently not present are depicted in italic.
            </option>
        </tab>
        
        <tab name="Collection type">      
            <option name="Create a collection of type 'set' (doesn't store duplicate values)">
                If checked, a collection column of type set is created. Set collections
                contain only distinct values, duplicates are deleted.
            </option>
            <option name="ignore missing values">
                If checked, missing values are ignored, i.e. not stored in collection
                cells.
            </option> 
            </tab>

        <tab name="Output table structure">      
            <option name="Remove aggregated columns from table">
                If checked, aggregated columns are removed from out put table.
            </option>
            <option name="Enter the name of the new column">
                Specifies the name of the new column containing the collection cells.
            </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Any input data">Any input data</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Input data with new collection column">
            The input data along with a newly appended collection column.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>