<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./../../../pca/pca_apply.png" type="Manipulator"
xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>PCA Apply</name>
	<shortDescription>Apply principal components projection</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node applies a projection to the principal components on the given
        	input data. The data model of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Principal_component_analysis">PCA</a> 
        	computation node can be applied to arbitrary data
        	to reduce it to a given number of dimensions.<br/>
        	The information preservation rates in the selection of the target dimensions give the expected
        	approximation rates based on the training data fed into the connected PCA Compute
        	node. These rates assume that data fed into the predictor is equally distributed
        	as the data the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Principal_component_analysis">PCA</a> was computed for initially.  
		</intro>
		<option name="Target dimensions">
			Determines the number of dimensions the input data is projected to. 
			The number of target dimensions can either be selected directly or by specifying the 
			minimal amount of information to be preserved.
			If selected directly, the number of dimensions must be lower than or equal to the number of input columns.
			If the PCA compute node is connected and executed the possible choices for information preservation 
			are directly mapped to the number of required columns.
		</option>
		<option name="Remove original data columns">
			If checked, the columns containing the input data are removed.
		</option>
		<option name="Fail if missing values are encountered">
			If checked, execution fails, when the selected columns contain missing values. 
			By default, rows containing missing values are ignored and not considered during the computation.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Transformation model">The Model used to reduce the data's dimensionality.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Table to transform">The data whose dimensionality shall be reduced.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Transformed data">The original data (if not excluded)
			plus columns for the projected dimensions.</outPort>
	</ports>
	<keywords>
		<keyword>principal component analysis</keyword>
	</keywords>
</knimeNode>
