<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="equals.png" type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Table Difference Finder</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Compares two tables with respect to their values as
		well as their column specs.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		The Table Difference Finder offers the functionality to compare two table by means of their
		values and table specs. Depending on the configuration the two input tables will be either be entirely
		be compared or solely respective a subset of the columns existent in the reference table, i.e., the first input.
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
		<option name="Compare entire tables">
		If this	option is checked all columns from the first as well as the second input will be compared against
		each other. Otherwise, the tables will solely be compared respective the selected columns of the 
		reference table. 
		<br/>
		<b>Note:</b> Row IDs are not being compared. 
		</option>
			<option name="Select columns from reference table">
				The list contains the names of those columns in
				the reference table to be included for the comparison. It allows you
				to select the columns manually (by moving them to the right panel),
				via wildcard/regex (all columns whose names match the wildcard/regex
				are included) or via type selection (all columns with a certain type
				are included). In case of manual selection, the behavior for new
				columns (i.e. that are not available at the time you configure the
				node)can be specified as either Enforce exclusion (new columns are
				excluded and therefore not used for comparison) or Enforce inclusion
				(new columns are included and therefore used for comparison).
			</option>
			<option name="Fail option:">
				<b>Never:</b>
				The Node will not fail on differences regarding the table spec nor
				the values.
				<br></br>
				<br></br>
				<b>Differing table specs:</b>
				The Node will fail if the tables feature differing specs.
				<br></br>
				<br></br>
				<b>Differing values:</b>
				The Node will fail if the tables feature differing specs and/or values.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table 1">Reference table.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Table 2">Table to check for compliance.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Value differences">
			Table exhibiting all differing entries.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Domain differences">
			Table containing a row for each unique column.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>

