<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./icon.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>t-SNE</name>
	<shortDescription>
		t-SNE is a manifold learning technique that learns a
		low-dimensional
		embedding of high-dimensional data.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			t-SNE is a manifold learning technique that learns low-dimensional
			embeddings for high-dimensional data.
			It is most often used for
			visualization purposes because it exploits
			the local relationships
			between data points and can
			hence capture non-linear structures in the
			data.
			Unlike other dimension reduction techniques like PCA, a learned
			t-SNE model
			can't be applied to new data.
			The t-SNE algorithm can be
			roughly summarized as two steps:
			<ol>
				<li>Create a probability distribution capturing the relationships
					between points in the high-dimensional space
				</li>
				<li>Find a low-dimensional space that resembles the probability
					dimension as good as possible
				</li>
			</ol>
			As t-SNE directly utilizes the data points, it is sensitive to the
			scale of the input features and for best results it is recommended to
			normalize the features
			using the Normalizer node.
			For further details
			check out this great
			<a
				href="mlexplained.com/2018/09/14/paper-dissected-visualizing-data-using-t-sne-explained/">blog post</a>
			or
			the original
			<a
				href="http://www.jmlr.org/papers/volume9/vandermaaten08a/vandermaaten08a.pdf">paper</a>
			.
			The implementation of this node is based on the
			<a href="http://haifengl.github.io/smile/">Smile - Statistical Machine Intelligence and Learning
				Engine</a>
			.
		</intro>

		<option name="Columns">
			Select the columns that are included by t-SNE i.e.
			the original features.
			Note that currently only numerical columns are
			supported.
		</option>
		<option name="Dimension(s) to reduce to">
			The number of dimension of the target embedding
			(for visualization typically 2 or 3).
		</option>
		<option name="Iterations">
			The number of learning iterations to perform. Too
			few iterations might
			result in a bad embedding while too many
			iterations take a long time
			to train.
		</option>
		<option name="Learning rate">
			The learning rate to use, i.e. how much the
			embedding changes in one
			iteration. A too small learning rate means
			that more iterations are
			required to reach a good embedding while a
			too large learning rate
			can result in unstable embeddings that change
			strongly between
			iterations.
		</option>
		<option name="Perplexity">
			Informally, the perplexity is the number of
			neighbors for each data point.
			Small perplexities focus more on local
			structure while larger perplexities take more global relationships
			into account.
			Typical values for the perplexity lay between 5 and 50.
		</option>
		<option name="Remove original data columns">
			Check this box if you want to remove the columns
			used to learn the embedding.
		</option>
		<option name="Fail if missing values are encountered">
			If this box is checked, the node fails if it
			encounters a missing value in one of the columns used for learning.
			Otherwise, rows containing missing values in the learning columns
			will be ignored during learning and the corresponding embedding
			consists of missing values.
		</option>
		<option name="Seed">
			Allows specifying a static seed to allow for
			reproducible results.
			NOTE: The Smile library is reproducible if and
			only if the VM argument smile.threads is 1.
			We set this property if it
			is not set during start up but we don't overwrite existing VM
			arguments, meaning if you set the smile.threads to anything other
			than 1 in your knime.ini, we won't overwrite this value and results
			will thus not be reproducible even if a static seed is provided.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Data">Input port for the data for which a
			low-dimensional embedding should be learned
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Embedded Data">The low-dimensional embedding
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>