<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="csvwriter.png" type="Sink"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>CSV Writer</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Writes a data table into a CSV file.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
            <p>
			This node writes out the input data table into a file or to a
			remote location denoted by an URL. The input data table
			must contain only string or numerical columns. Other column types are not
			supported.
			</p>

            <p>
            <i>This node can access a variety of different</i>
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/2021-06/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#analytics-platform-file-systems"><i>file systems.</i></a> 
            <i>More information about file handling in KNIME can be found in the official</i> 
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html"><i>File Handling Guide.</i></a>
            </p>

		</intro>
		<tab name="Settings">
			<description>
				General settings regarding the output file location and
				formats.
			</description>
			<option name="Write to">
				Select a file system in which you want to store the file. There
				are
				four default file system options to choose from:
				<br />
				<ul>
					<li><i>Local File System:</i> Allows you to select a location in your
	                    local system.
	                </li>
	                <li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Allows you to write to a mountpoint.
	                	When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to choose the mountpoint.
	                	Unconnected mountpoints are greyed out but can still be selected (note that browsing is disabled in this case).
	                	Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.
	                	A mountpoint is displayed in red if it was previously selected but is no longer available.
	                	You won't be able to save the dialog as long as you don't select a valid i.e. known mountpoint.
	                </li>
	                <li><i>Relative to:</i> Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path
						relative to the current mountpoint, current workflow or the current workflow's data area.
	                When selected a new drop-down menu appears to choose which of the three options to use.
	                </li>
					<li><i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i> Allows to specify a URL (e.g. file://, http:// or knime:// protocol). 
	                    When selected, a spinner appears that allows you to specify the desired connection and write timeout in milliseconds.
	                    In case it takes longer to connect to the host / write the file, the node fails to execute.
	                    Browsing is disabled for this option.
	                </li>
				</ul>
				It is possible to use other file systems with this node. Therefore,
				you have to enable the file system connection input port of this
				node
				by clicking the
				<b>...</b>
				in the bottom left corner of the node's icon and choose
				<i>Add File System Connection port</i>
				.
				<br />
				Afterwards, you can simply connect the desired connector node to this node.
				The file system connection will then be shown in the drop-down menu.
				It is greyed out if the file system is not connected in which case you have to (re)execute the connector node first.
				Note: The default file systems listed above can't be selected if a file system is provided via the input port.
			</option>

			<option name="File/URL">
			Enter a URL when writing to <i>Custom/KNIME URL</i>, otherwise enter a path to a file. The
				required syntax of a path depends on the chosen file system, such as &quot;C:\path\to\file&quot; (Local
				File System on Windows) or  &quot;/path/to/file&quot; (Local
	            File System on Linux/MacOS and Mountpoint). For file systems connected via input port, the node
	            description of the respective connector node describes the required path format.
				You can also choose a previously selected file from the drop-down list, or select a location
				from the &quot;Browse...&quot; dialog.
				Note that browsing is disabled in some cases:
				<ul>
					<li><i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i> Browsing is always disabled.</li>
					<li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Browsing is disabled if the selected mountpoint isn't connected.
					Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.</li>
					<li><i>File systems provided via input port:</i>
					Browsing is disabled if the connector node hasn't been executed since the workflow has been opened.
					(Re)execute the connector node to enable browsing.</li>
				</ul>
                <i>The location can be exposed as or automatically set via a 
                </i><a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#path">
                <i>path flow variable.</i></a>
		</option>
			<option name="Create missing folders">Select if the folders of the selected
				output
				location should be created if they do not already exist. If
				this
				option is unchecked, the node will fail if a folder does not
				exist.
			</option>
			<option name="If exists">
				Specify the behavior of the node in case the output file already exists.
				<ul>
					<li><i>Overwrite:</i> Will replace any existing file.
					</li>
					<li><i>Append:</i> Will append the input table to the end of the file (possibly skipping the column header)
					</li>
					<li><i>Fail:</i> Will issue an error during the node's execution (to prevent unintentional overwrite).
					</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
			<option name="Column delimiter">
				The character string delimiting columns. Use '\t' for tab character.
			</option>
			<option name="Row delimiter">
				Select the line break variation you want to use as row delimiter while writing the CSV file.
				<ul>
					<li><i>System Default:</i> use the line break of the system on which the node is executed.
					</li>
					<li><i>Linux/Unix Line Break:</i> use LF (line feed) as in Linux/Unix systems.
					</li>
					<li><i>Windows Line Break:</i> use CR+LF (a carriage return followed by a line feed) as in Windows/Dos systems.
					</li>
					<li><i>Mac OS9 Line Break:</i> use CR (a carriage return only) as in old MacOS (before MacOS 9) systems.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
			<option name="Quote char">
				The quote character used to enclose values with. See the advanced tab to specify what
				kind of values should be enclosed within quotes.
			</option>
			<option name="Quote escape char">
				The character is used for escaping quotes inside an already quoted
				value.
			</option>
			<option name="Write column header">
				If checked, the column names will be written out in the first line of the output file.
			</option>
			<option name="Don't write column headers if file exists">
				If checked, the column headers will not be
				written when the output
				is appended to the already existing output
				file.
				This is particularly useful when the CSV Writer is
				used in a
				loop to report results. This option is ignored
				when the column header
				is not written anyway or the file append option
				is unchecked (see
				below).
			</option>
			<option name="Write row ID">If checked, the row IDs will be
				added to the
				output, as first item in each line.
			</option>
		</tab>

		<tab name="Advanced Settings">
			<description>
				In the Advanced tab, you can specify when to quote values and how to handle the formatting of
				numeric values before writing them to file. There is also an option to write files compressed
				with GZip compression.
			</description>
			<option name="Quote values: always">Every data item written out is
				placed between quotation marks. (The missing value pattern is not
				quoted though.)
				</option>
			<option name="Quote values: if needed">Quotes are only placed around a
				data item that contains the data separator (specified in the Advanced
				tab) or if it equals the missing value pattern. The right quote pattern
				will be replaced if it appears in a quoted data item.
				</option>
			<option name="Quote values: strings only">Integer and floating point
				numbers are not quoted, all other data items are. (Selecting the decimal
				point as data separator will lead to an output that can&apos;t be read in
				again.) The right quote is replaced in quoted items.
				</option>
			<option name="Quote values: never">No data item is placed between quotation
				marks. You should specify a replacement pattern for the data separator,
				if it occurs in the data item.
			</option>
			<option name="Replace column separator with">
				Specify a replacement for the value used as a column separator.
				Used only if the never option is selected for Quote values.
			</option>
			<option name="Decimal Separator">
				Here you can enter a character that is used as decimal separator for
				floating point numbers. It replaces the default character '.' then.
			</option>
			<option name="Use scientific format for very large and very small values">
				Check this if you want very large and very small floating point
				numbers to be written in scientific notation (e.g., 1.0E9 instead of
				1,000,000,000).
			</option>
			<option name="Append .0 suffix for decimal values without fractions">
				Check this if you want to write every decimal value with .0 suffix even though
				the value doesn't contain any fractional part. (e.g., the value 12 will be written as 12.0
				if it is coming from a decimal column). Use with caution as this could lead to unnecessary
				increase of the file size. This doesn't affect the way to write values from
				integer columns. The option is ignored if we are using a scientific format.
			</option>
		   <option name="Replace missing value with">
				Set this option to replace missing values from the input table with specific text when writing.
			</option>
			<option name="Compress output file (gzip)">
				Check this if you want to compress the output file using gzip compression.
			</option>

		</tab>
		<tab name="Comment Header">
			<description>In the Comment Header tab you can add a
				comment header to the beginning of the output. Either specify your
				own comment line(s) or choose from the predefined items.
				If you check one of the options you must also enter a comment line marker.
			</description>
			<option name="the user (login) name">If checked, the login
				name of the user that
				created the file (probably you!) is inserted.
			</option>
			<option name="the current execution time">If checked, a
				comment line with the current execution time
				and date is added.
			</option>
			<option name="the input table name">If checked, a comment
				line is added showing the
				name of the table the data was read from.
			</option>
			<option name="the following text">If you check this, you can enter
				any free text, that  will be added then to the comment header.
			</option>
			<option name="Comment Line Marker">
				If you have checked at least one of the content
				options, you must provide a comment line marker that is used as a prefix for each
				comment line.
			</option>
			<option name="Comment Indentation">
				If you have checked at least one of the content
				options, you can specify an indentation string, i.e., a prefix for
				every comment line.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Encoding">
			<option name="File Encoding">
				To write a CSV file with a different encoding,
				you can select a character set in this tab (UTF-8,
				UTF-16, etc.), or
				specify any other encoding supported by your Java VM. The default
				value uses the default
				encoding of the Java VM, which may depend on
				the locale or the Java property &quot;file.encoding&quot; </option>
		</tab>
		<link
			href="https://www.knime.com/knime-introductory-course/chapter4/section1/write-data-to-a-csv-file">
			KNIME E-Learning Course: Write Data to a CSV File
		</link>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input table">The data table to write out.</inPort>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0" name="File system connection"
			group-identifier="File System Connection">
			The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
	</ports>

</knimeNode>
