<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./s3connection16x16.png" type="Source" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Amazon S3 Connection</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Configures the connection information used to
        connect to Amazon S3.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	<p>
        		This node configures the connection information that will be used to connect to Amazon S3. Using this 
        		connection the other KNIME remote file handling nodes can be used to create directory, list, delete, 
        		download and upload files from and to Amazon S3. 
        	</p>
        	<p>
        		The connection information is encoded in the format <i>s3://accessKeyId@region</i>. The protocol is 
        		<i>s3</i> and the host is the region name. The first folder path is the bucket name and the rest is the 
        		object key, e.g. <i>s3://AZHC7SNUZCTTSGGRGBXG@eu-west-1/knime-bucket/data/iris.data</i> defines the object 
        		<i>data/iris.data</i> in the bucket <i>knime-bucket</i>, which is stored in the region <i>eu-west-1</i>. 
        		The access key ID is <i>AZHC7SNUZCTTSGGRGBXG</i>.
        	</p>        	
        	<p>
        		The region name, the bucket name and the object key are needed in order to delete, download, or upload objects 
        		from a list. The access key ID is not needed. For instance, to delete the above mentioned object <i>iris.data</i>,
        		it is needed to encode the path to <i>s3://eu-west-1/knime-bucket/data/iris.data</i> in the list.        		
        	</p>
        	<p>
        		For further documentation please take a look at the <a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/gsg/GetStartedWithS3.html">AWS Documentation</a>.
        	</p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Connection name">The name of the connection</option>
        <option name="Authentication">
        Method for authentication
        	<br/>
        	<b>Workflow Credentials</b>
        	<br/>
        	Use workflow credentials to determine the access key ID and the secret access key. 
        	The login is used as the access key ID and the password is used as the secret access key.
        	<br/>
        	<b>Access Key ID and Secret Access Key</b>
        	<br/>
        	The AWS access key ID used to authenticate.
        	<br/>
        	The AWS secret access key used to authenticate.
        	<br/>
        	<b>Default Credential Provider Chain</b>
        	<br/>
        	When selected the default credential provider chain is used for authentication. Default location is "~/.aws/credentials" on most platforms. 
       	</option>
       	<option name="Switch Role">
			Switch your IAM role. For more information see: <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/IAM/latest/UserGuide/id_roles_use_switch-role-console.html">Switching to a Role</a>
        	<br/>
        	<b>Account</b>
        	<br/>
			The 12-digit account ID for which the role should be assumed.
        	<br/>
        	<b>Role</b>
        	<br/>
        	The name of the role that should be assumed.
       	</option>
        <option name="Region">
        	The Amazon S3 geographical region to store the buckets that the user creates.
        </option>
        <option name="Timeout">
        	The timeout in milliseconds when initially establishing a connection.
        </option>
        <option name="Test connection">
        	Open dialog that tests the current connection.
        	<p>
        	Note: The connection will also succeed if you have restricted permissions for file listing in S3.
        	In that case browsing in the file handling nodes will not be possible but paths can be entered manually.
        	</p>
        </option>
        
        <option name="Use SSE (Server Side Encryption)">
        	If checked, uploads will use server side encryption.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="Local File System Connection">A flow variable containing the named local connection 
		</outPort>
	</ports>        
</knimeNode>
