<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="interval_variables_looper.png" type="LoopStart" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>Interval Loop Start</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Node at the start of a loop
	</shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            The Interval LoopStart is the node that starts a loop which increases a variable
            within a user-defined interval by a certain amount. This is very handy for nodes
            inside a loop that take a continuous parameter. The current value is accessible via the
            scope variable
            <tt>loop_value</tt>
            .
            At the end of the loop you need LoopEnd, which collects the results from
            all loop iterations. All nodes in between are executed as many times as you specify in the dialog
            of LoopStart.
            <p>
                The input ports are just passed through to the output ports. You can add an arbitrary number of
                port pairs by using the &#8220;&#8230;&#8221; menu.
            </p>
        </intro>
        <option name="From">The interval start value (inclusive).</option>
        <option name="To">The interval end value (inclusive).</option>
        <option name="Step">
            The step size by which the value is increased after each iteration. Negative step sizes are possible, if
            <i>from</i>
            is greater than
            <i>to</i>
        </option>
        <option name="Loop variable is">
            Select the type of the variable that is exposed by the node (integers, longs or doubles).
            The node creates variables for <i>from, to, step</i> and the current <i>value.</i>
            Keep in mind that this only affects the type of the variables. Internally doubles are used
            to keep track of the loop state. This means that the values may be rounded to fit the specified
            type.
        </option>
        <option name="Variable prefix">The prefix of the variable names</option>
        <link href="https://www.knime.com/knime-introductory-course/chapter7/section2">
            KNIME E-Learning Course: Section 7.2. Re-executing Workflow Parts: Loops
        </link>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <dynInPort name="Any port object" group-identifier="Pass through" insert-before="0">
            The input data, which can be a data table or any other arbitrary port object.
        </dynInPort>
        <dynOutPort name="Unaltered input" group-identifier="Pass through" insert-before="0">
            The unaltered input object
        </dynOutPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
