<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./elementselector.png" type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
	<name>Top k Selector</name>
	<shortDescription>Selects the top k rows according to user-defined criteria.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			The node behaves the same as a combination of the
			<b>Sorter</b>
			node followed by a
			<b>Row Filter</b>
			that only keeps the first k rows of the table except for the order of
			the rows which depends on the
			<i>Output order</i>
			settings.
			Note, however, that the implementation of this node is more
			efficient then the node combination above.
			In the dialog, select
			the
			columns according to which the data should be selected. For each
			column you can also specify
			whether a larger or smaller value is
			considered as superior.
		</intro>
		<option name="Add columns">If you want to extend the selection criteria
			to a
			higher number of columns as displayed, set the number of columns
			at
			the bottom and click 'new columns' to add them to the dialog.
		</option>
		<option name="Number of rows">The number of rows to select from the input table.
		</option>
		<option name="Move Missing Cells to end of sorted list">If selected, missing
			values are always considered
			to be inferior to present cells.
		</option>
		<option name="Output order">
			Specifies constraints of the order of the output
			<ul>
				<li>No order: No specific order is required for the rows in the
					output. This is the best option in terms of runtime.</li>
				<li>Retain order: Ensures that the rows in the output are the same
					as in the input.</li>
				<li>Sort output: The rows in the output are sorted according to the
					specified criteria.</li>
			</ul>
		</option>
		<option name="Top k Mode">
			Specifies the mode for the top k selection of the output
			<ul>
				<li>Top k rows: Returns the top k rows based on their first
					occurrence in the input table.</li>
				<li>Top k rows with unique values: Returns all occurrences of the
					top k rows.</li>
			</ul>
		</option>

	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input Table">Table to select rows from.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Top k Table">A table containing the top k rows.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
