<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./switches_any_end.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>CASE Switch End</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Merges one or more active branches of a workflow. The type and number of input ports can be dynamically chosen.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
                This node complements the CASE Switch Start node. It merges the created branches into a single output
                port. Typically, only one branch is active, and the content on that branch is forwarded to the output 
                port. In case the Switch is used for data ports, additional options for merging the data tables on 
                multiple active branches are offered. <br/>
                The type of the input and output ports can be chosen when adding an
                output port using the &#8220;&#8230;&#8221; menu. The type of the output port can be changed by 
                removing and adding it again with a new type.
            </p>
            <p>
                <i>Note for flow variable ports:</i>
                    The values for existing flow variables will always be those at the top-most port of the end node, 
                    even if they are changed on an active branch (that is not connected to the top-most port). 
                    However, new variables created in any active branch will behave as expected.
                    If you want to change the value of existing variables, please create a new flow variable, and use
                    its value to overwrite the old variable after the CASE Switch End node. <br/>
                    If all branches are inactive, the flow variables of the top branch are passed through.
            </p>
			<p>
				To migrate from the deprecated CASE Switch Model (End) node, select
				Generic Port when creating the output port.
			</p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="&#8220;Data&#8221; Type Settings">
            <option name="If multiple inputs are active">
                Choose the expected behavior of the node if two or more inputs are active.
                <ul>
                    <li><i>Merge tables:</i> tries to merge the input tables <i>(default)</i></li>
                    <li><i>Fail:</i> the node fails</li>
                    <li><i>Use first non-inactive input:</i> output the first active port, ignoring any subsequent active ports</li>
                </ul>
                In the case all inputs are inactive the node itself will pass on and an inactive object.
            </option>
            <option name="Skip Rows">
                Duplicate row identifiers (RowID) occurring in additional active
                tables are not appended to the output table. This option is
                relatively memory intensive as it needs to cache the RowIDs in
                order to find duplicates.
            </option>
            <option name="Append suffix">
                The output table will contain all rows, but
                duplicate row identifiers are labeled with a suffix. Similar to
                the "Skip Rows" option this method is also memory intensive.
            </option>
            <option name="Enable hiliting">
                Enables hiliting between both inputs and the concatenated output
                table.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="&#8220;Other&#8221; Type Settings">
            <option name="If multiple inputs are active">
                Choose the expected behavior of the node if two or more inputs are active.
                <ul>
                    <li><i>Fail:</i> the node fails <i>(default)</i></li>
                    <li><i>Use first non-inactive input:</i> output the first active port, ignoring any subsequent active ports</li>
                </ul>
                In the case all inputs are inactive the node itself will pass on and an inactive object.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <link href="https://www.knime.com/knime-introductory-course/chapter7/section1/creation-and-usage-of-flow-variables">
            KNIME E-Learning Course: Creation and usage of Flow Variables in a KNIME workflow
        </link>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <dynInPort name="Input" group-identifier="Input" insert-before="0">
            Select the input port type and connect it. Only one input port can be selected at
            a time. If the input port is removed, all output ports are also removed.
        </dynInPort>
        <dynOutPort name="Input" group-identifier="Output" insert-before="0">
            The output ports. They are only present and editable if an input port type was
            selected and always have the same type. At least two outputs are required.
        </dynOutPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
