<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="pythonscript.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>CASE Switch (&#8230;) (Start)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Outputs the input data to exactly one of the output ports. The type as well
        as the amount of output ports can dynamically chosen.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This nodes takes the data from the input port and moves it
            to exactly one active output branch. The type of data can be chosen by adding an
            input port using the &#8220;&#8230;&#8221; menu. No output ports can be added before an
            input port has been selected. The type of the input port can be changed by removing and
            adding it again with a new type. Keep in mind that this removes any connections of the
            output ports.

            <h4>Migrating from the old &#8220;CASE Switch [&#8230;] (Start)&#8221; nodes</h4>
                To get the same results as the old nodes you have to select the following types:
            <table>
                <tr><th>Node name</th><th>Port type name</th></tr>
                <tr><td>CASE Switch Data (Start)</td><td>Data</td></tr>
                <tr><td>CASE Switch Variable (Start)</td><td>Flow Variable</td></tr>
                <tr><td>CASE Switch Model (Start)</td><td>Generic Port</td></tr>
            </table>
        </intro>
        <option name="Select active port">
            Select the active output port. This can be controlled by an integer or string variable and used to
            create a string variable.
        </option>
        <option name="Activate all outputs during configuration step">
            When set the node will keep all outputs active during workflow configuration (that is, while
            the traffic light of the node is &#8220;yellow&#8221;). This allows the configuration of connected downstream nodes and
            simplifies the workflow design at the expense of additional configuration calls of nodes that are later on
            inactive. It's recommended to switch this flag off for production workflows as this avoids unnecessary
            configuration calls of the inactive branches.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
		<dynInPort name="Input" group-identifier="Input" insert-before="0">
            Select the input port type and connect it. Only one input port can be selected at
            a time. If the input port is removed, all output ports are also removed.
		</dynInPort>
		<dynOutPort name="Output" group-identifier="Output" insert-before="0">
            The output ports. They are only present and editable if an input port type was
            selected and always have the same type. At least two outputs are required.
		</dynOutPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
