<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./switches_any_start.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>CASE Switch Start</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Routes the input to a selectable output port. The type and number of output ports can be dynamically chosen.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	<p>
	            This node routes its input to a selectable output port, allowing different branches of the workflow to
	            be activated manually or using a flow variable. The input port type can be chosen when adding an
	            input port using the &#8220;&#8230;&#8221; menu. The type can be changed by removing the input port 
	            and adding it again.
        	</p>
			<p>
				To migrate from the deprecated CASE Switch Model (Start) node, select
				Generic Port when creating the input port.
			</p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Select active port">
            Select the active output port. This can be controlled by an integer or string variable and used to
            create a string variable.
        </option>
        <option name="Activate all outputs during configuration step">
            When set the node will keep all outputs active during workflow configuration (that is, while
            the traffic light of the node is &#8220;yellow&#8221;). This allows the configuration of connected downstream nodes and
            simplifies the workflow design at the expense of additional configuration calls of nodes that are later on
            inactive. It's recommended to switch this flag off for production workflows as this avoids unnecessary
            configuration calls of the inactive branches.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
		<dynInPort name="Input" group-identifier="Input" insert-before="0">
            Select the input port type and connect it. Only one input port can be selected at
            a time. If the input port is removed, all output ports are also removed.
		</dynInPort>
		<dynOutPort name="Output" group-identifier="Output" insert-before="0">
            The output ports. They are only present and editable if an input port type was
            selected and always have the same type. At least two outputs are required.
		</dynOutPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
