<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./columnfilter.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.6" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.6 http://knime.org/node/v3.6.xsd">
    <name>Column Filter (PMML)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        The Column Filter allows columns to be excluded from the input table.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node allows columns to be filtered from the input table while 
            only the remaining columns are passed to the output table. Within 
            the dialog, columns can be moved between the Include and Exclude 
            list.
        </intro>
        
        <tab name="Manual Selection">
			<option name="Include">
				This list contains the names of the columns in the input table
				that are included in the output table.
			</option>
			
			<option name="Exclude">
				This list contains the names of the columns in the input table
				that are excluded from the output table.
			</option>

            <option name="Filter">
                Use one of these fields to filter either the Include or Exclude
                list for certain column names or name substrings.
            </option>
            
            <option name="Buttons">
                Use these buttons to move columns between the Include and Exclude 
                list. Single-arrow buttons will move all selected columns.
                Double-arrow buttons will move all columns (filtering is taken into
                account).
            </option>
            
            <option name="Enforce Inclusion">
                Select this option to enforce the current inclusion list to stay
                the same even if the input table specification changes. If some
                of the included columns are not available anymore, a warning
                is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
                exclusion list.)
            </option>

            <option name="Enforce Exclusion">
                Select this option to enforce the current exclusion list to stay
                the same even if the input table specification changes. If some
                of the excluded columns are not available anymore, a warning
                is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
                inclusion list.)
            </option>
        </tab>

        <tab name="Wildcard/Regex Selection">
        	<option name="">
				Type a search pattern which matches columns to move into the
				Include list. You can use either Wildcards ('?' matching any
				character, '*' matching a sequence of any characters) or Regex.
				You can specify if your pattern should be case sensitive.
			</option>
        </tab>

        <tab name="Type selection">
        	<option name="">
				Select the column types that you want to include. Column types
				that are currently not present are depicted in italic.
			</option>
        </tab>

		<link href="https://www.knime.com/knime-introductory-course/chapter3/section1/column-filter">
			KNIME E-Learning Course: Column Filter
		</link>

        <link href="http://download.oracle.com/javase/6/docs/api/java/util/regex/Pattern.html">
            Java API documentation about regex patterns
        </link>

        <link href="http://download.oracle.com/javase/6/docs/api/java/util/regex/Matcher.html">
            Java API documentation about regex matching
        </link>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Table to be filtered">
            Table from which columns are to be excluded.
        </inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="PMML">
            A PMML document.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Filtered table">
            Table excluding selected columns.
        </outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="PMML">
            The input PMML excluding the selected columns.
        </outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
