<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./collumnappend.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Column Appender</name>

	<shortDescription>
		A fast way to reverse the operation of a splitter
		node.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
	<intro>
		The Column Appender takes two or more tables and quickly combines them by
		appending their columns according to the order of the tables at the input 
		ports. It simply appends columns from the second input table to the first 
		input table and does the same for any subsequent table if additional 
		(dynamic) ports were added. The node performs a simple and straight
		forward join operation but can be faster if certain preconditions are met.
		For more details please read the description of the "Identical row keys
		and table lengths"-option below. When in doubt, use the Joiner.
		<br></br>
		If the input tables share some column names, the offending column
		names from the bottom tables will be appended with "(#1), (#2) and so on".		
	</intro>
	<tab name="Options">
		<option name="Identical row keys and table lengths">
			If the row keys in both input tables exactly match (i.e. the row key
			names, their order, and their number have to match) this option can
			be checked in order to allow a faster execution with less memory consumption. 
			If the row keys (names, order, number) don't match exactly the node execution 
			will fail.
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			If this option
			<i>is NOT checked</i>
			the result table is newly created. This might result in a longer processing time. 
			However, in this case the number of rows in the input tables can differ and missing 
			values are added accordingly. The row keys are either generated new or taken from 
			one of the input tables (see options below).
		</option>
		<option name = "Generate new row keys">
		    Row keys are newly generated. If one of the input table is longer than the other, 
		    missing values are inserted accordingly.
		</option>
		<option name = "Use row keys from one of the input tables">
			The row keys of the table with the selected index are used. Tables with less number 
			of rows will be filled with missing values accordingly. And tables with more number
			of rows will be truncated.
		</option>
	</tab>

</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table 0">If the option "Identical row keys and table lengths" is checked: a sorted table with n rows. Otherwise a table without restrictions.</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Table 1">If the option "Identical row keys and table lengths" is checked: Another sorted table with n rows. Otherwise a table without restrictions.</inPort>
        <dynInPort insert-before="2" name="Table ..." group-identifier="input"> Table contributing subsequent columns. </dynInPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Appended table">A table with the columns from all input tables
			(Table 0, Table 1, Table ...)
		</outPort>
	</ports>
	<keywords>
		<keywords>Join</keywords>
	</keywords>
</knimeNode>

