<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./variable_creator.png" type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Variable Creator</name>
	<shortDescription>Creates flow variables for use in the workflow.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				This node allows creating flow variables of different types.
				The constant default values of the variables can be changed and
				the node will chose some reasonable start values for these defaults
				on creation.
				<br />
				<i>Note:</i>
					The variables defined by this node take precedence over upstream ones (on the Variable Inport).
					Thus upstream variables will get overridden by defined variables with the same name and
					type. The node will issue a warning in the case this happens.<br />
					It is possible to define variables with the same name but different types but this will
					probably lead to unexpected behavior downstream and should be avoided.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Add">
			This button can be used to define a new variable.
		</option>
		<option name="Type">
			This is the type of the variable to create. Depending on the type the requirements for the default value may
			change.
			<br />
				The following five basic data types are supported:
			<br />
			<ul>
				<li>
					<i>String</i>.
						A string of characters. This is the default if a new variable is created.
					<br />
					<i>Note:</i>
						The node will issue a warning if the string is empty or does only contain spaces.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Integer</i>.
						An integer number with possible values from 2&#179;&#185;-1 to -2&#179;&#185;.
						The value must be a valid number (consisting only of an optional sign
						(&#8220;+&#8221;/&#8220;-&#8221;) and &#8220;0&#8221;-&#8220;9&#8221;) and be in the range above.<br />
						If the size of your value exceeds the limits above, you can try to use a <i>Long</i>
						or <i>Double</i> value instead.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Long</i>.
						An integer number with possible values from 2&#8310;&#170;-1 to -2&#8310;&#170;.
						The value must be a valid number (consisting only of an optional sign
						(&#8220;+&#8221;/&#8220;-&#8221;) and &#8220;0&#8221;-&#8220;9&#8221;) and be in the range above.<br />
						If the size of your value exceeds the limits above, you can try to use a <i>Double</i>
						value instead.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Double</i>.
						A floating point decimal number with possible values from around 4.9&#183;10&#8315;&#179;&#178;&#8308; to 1.8&#183;10&#179;&#8304;&#8312;
						in both the positive and negative range.<br />
						The value must be a valid number (consisting only of an optional sign
						(&#8220;+&#8221;/&#8220;-&#8221;) and &#8220;0&#8221;-&#8220;9&#8221;).
						You can specify an exponent	by appending &#8220;e&#8221; followed by the exponent. Apart from a
						numeric value you can also specify one of the following three (case-sensitive) special values:
							<i>Infinity</i> for positive infinity,
							<i>-Infinity</i> for negative infinity and
							<i>NaN</i> for &#8220;Not a Number&#8221;.<br />
						If the number is too big or too small, it may be converted into one of the these special values.
								(You will be warned if this happens).<br />
						You should keep in mind that you may loose some precision
						for big values or values that are very close to zero.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Boolean</i>.
						A truth value that can be either &#8220;true&#8221; or &#8220;false&#8221;.
					<br />
					<i>Note:</i>
						Any other value will be interpreted as &#8220;false&#8221;.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</option>
		<option name="Variable Name">
			This is the name of the variable. You can use any characters to define your name. However,
			a name must not be empty or be used by other variables you have already defined in the node
			(regardless of the variable type).
		</option>
		<option name="Value">
			The value of the variable. It must comply with the limitations of the type described above.
		</option>
		<option name="Move/Remove variable">
            To improve readability of your variables (e.g. grouping all values of a specific type) you can change their order by using the arrow buttons at the end of the row.
        <br />
			If you wish to delete a variable definition, you can use the button with the bin icon next to
			the move buttons.
		</option>
		<link
			href="https://www.knime.com/knime-introductory-course/chapter7/section1/creation-and-usage-of-flow-variables">
			KNIME E-Learning Course: Creation and usage of Flow Variables in
			a KNIME workflow
		</link>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
	<outPort index="0" name="Created flow variables">Created flow variables</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
