<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="filefoldermetainfo16x16.png" type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1
	http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Files/Folders Meta Info</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Adds meta information about files/folders to the table.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
            <p>
			This node adds meta information about the files and folders referenced by the selected column. At least the
			following information are covered:
			<ul>
				<li>
					<i>Directory:</i> 
					Indicator whether or not the path points to a directory
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Size:</i> 
					The size of the file/folder
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Size (human readable):</i> 
					The size of the file/folder in a human readable form
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Last modified date:</i> 
					The last time the file was modified
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Created date:</i> 
					The time the file was created
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Exists:</i> 
					Indicator whether or not the file/folder exists
				</li>
			</ul>
			</p>

            <p>
            <i>This node can access a variety of different</i>
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/2021-06/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#analytics-platform-file-systems"><i>file systems.</i></a> 
            <i>More information about file handling in KNIME can be found in the official</i> 
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html"><i>File Handling Guide.</i></a>
            </p>

		</intro>
		<option name="Column name">
			Column containing the paths to the files/folders whose meta information must be extracted.
		</option>
		<option name="Fail if file/folder does not exist">
			If checked, the node fails if any of the referenced files or folders does not exist.
		</option>
		<option name="Calculate overall folder size">
			If checked, the size of the folder itself plus everything located within this folder is being calculated,
			otherwise solely the folder's size is being calculated.
		</option>
		<option name="Append permissions">
			If checked, the file/folder permissions, i.e., <i>readable</i>, <i>writable</i>, and <i>executable</i> 
			flags will be appended to the output. In case the file system does not provide access to these attributes 
			missing values are written to the output. 
			<br/>
			<i>Note:</i> The meaning of the executable flag with respect to folders is file system depended, e.g., on 
			UNIX systems this flag is <tt>true</tt> if the JVM has permissions to search the directory.
		</option>
        <option name="Append POSIX attributes">
            If checked, a set of columns that capture POSIX attributes (owner, group and permission bits) will be appended to the output.
            In case the file system does not provide access to these attributes missing values are written to the output.
            <br/>
            <i>Note:</i> The meaning of the permission bits depend on the actual file system.
        </option>

	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input Table">Table that contains a path column.
		</inPort>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0" name="File system connection"
			group-identifier="File System Connection">
			The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<outPort name="Output Table" index="0">
			Input table plus additional columns storing the files/folders meta information.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
