<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="featureselection-start.png" type="LoopStart">
	<name>Feature Selection Loop Start (2:2)</name>

	<shortDescription>Start node for a feature selection loop</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node is the start of the feature selection loop. The
			feature selection loop allows you to select, from all the features in
			the input data set, the subset of features that is best for model
			construction. With this node you determine (i) which features/columns
			are to be held fixed in the selection process. These constant or
			"static" features/columns are included in each loop iteration and are
			exempt from elimination; (ii) which selection strategy is to be used
			on the other (variable) features/columns and its settings; and (iii)
			the specific settings of the selected strategy.
			This node has two in and out ports. The respective
			first
			port is intended for training data and the second port for test
			data.
			The same filter is applied to both tables and they will
			therefore
			always contain the same columns.
		</intro>

		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Static and Variable Features">Columns can be selected manually or by means of
				regular expressions. The columns in the left pane are the static
				columns, those in the right pane the variable columns. If you want to
				learn a supervised model (e.g. classification or regression), at least one static
				column and more than one variable column will be needed. For an unsupervised model
				(e.g. clustering), no constant column but only variable columns will be needed.
				Columns can be moved from one pane to the other by clicking on the appropriate button in
				the middle.
			</option>
			<option name="Feature selection strategy">
				Here you can choose between the selection strategies: Forward
				Feature Selection, Backward Feature Elimination, 
				<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genetic_algorithm">Genetic Algorithm</a> and Random.
			</option>
			<option name="Use threshold for number of features">
				Check this option if you want to set a bound for
				the number of selected
				features. Since Forward Feature Selection adds
				features while
				Backward Feature Elimination subtracts them, this will
				be an upper
				bound for Forward Feature Selection and a lower bound for
				Backward
				Feature Elimination.
			</option>
			<option name="Select threshold for number of features">
				Set the upper or lower bound for the number of
				selected features.
			</option>
			<option name="Use lower bound for number of features">
				Check this option if you want to set a lower bound for the number of
				selected features.
			</option>
			<option name="Use upper bound for number of features">
				Check this option if you want to set an upper bound for the number of
				selected features.
			</option>
			<option name="Population size">Set the number of individuals in each
				population. Changing this value directly influences the maximal number of loop 
				iterations which is	<i>Population size * (Number of generations + 1)</i>. This is just an upper bound,
				usually less iterations will be necessary.
			</option>
			<option name="Max. number of generations">
				Set the number of generations. Changing this value directly influences the maximal number of loop 
				iterations which is	<i>Population size * (Number of generations + 1)</i>. This is just an upper bound,
				usually less iterations will be necessary.
			</option>
			<option name="Max. number of iterations">
				Set the number of iterations. This is an upper bound. If the same feature subset is randomly generated 
				for a second time, it won't be processed again but will be counted as iteration. Furthermore, if early
				stopping is enabled, the algorithm may stop before the max. number of iterations is reached.
			</option>
			<option name="Use static random seed"> Choose a seed to get reproducible results.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Advanced Options">
			<option name="Selection strategy">
				Choose the strategy to use for the
				<a
					href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Selection_(genetic_algorithm)">selection of offspring</a>.
			</option>
			<option name="Fraction of survivors"> Set the fraction of survivors during evaluation of the next generation.
			<i>1 - fraction of survivors</i> defines the fraction of offspring which is evaluated for the next generation.
			</option>
			<option name="Elitism rate"> Set the fraction of the best
				individuals within a generation that are transfered to the next generation
				without alternation.
			</option>
			<option name="Crossover strategy">
				Choose the strategy to use for
				<a
					href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crossover_(genetic_algorithm)"> crossover</a>.
			</option>
			<option name="Crossover rate">
				Set the crossover rate used to alter
				offspring.
			</option>
			<option name="Mutation rate">
				Set the mutation rate used to alter
				offspring.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable early stopping">
				Check this option if you want to enable early stopping which means that the algorithm stops after a 
				specified number of generations/iterations without improvement. If using the random strategy, this is based 
				on a moving average whereby the size of the moving window is the same number as the specified 
        		number of iterations. If the ratio of improvement is lower than a specified tolerance, the search stops.
			</option>
			<option name="Number of generations/iterations without improvement">
				Set the number of generations/iterations without improvement (or with less improvement than the specified 
				tolerance in case of random strategy) used for early stopping. In case of random strategy it also defines 
				the size of the moving window. 
			</option>
			<option name="Tolerance">
	        	The tolerance used for early stopping which defines the threshold for the ratio of improvement. If the ratio is
	        	lower than the threshold, the strategy stops.
        	</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table containing features and constant columns">A data table containing all features
		and static columns needed for the feature selection. (Trainingdata)</inPort>
		<inPort name="Table with same structure as the first one" index="1">
		A data table containing all features
		and static columns needed for the feature selection. (Testdata)</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Filtered table">The input table with some columns filtered out. (Training data)</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Filtered table">The input table with some columns filtered out. (Test data)</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
