<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="reader.png" type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>PMML Reader</name>

	<shortDescription>
        Reads models from a PMML compliant XML file.
    </shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>This node reads any PMML model from a PMML compliant XML file.
		</intro>
		<option name="Read from">
			Select a file system which stores the model you want to read. There
			are four default file system options to choose from:
			<br />
			<ul>
				<li>Local File System: Allows you to select a file from your
					local
					system.
				</li>
				<li>Relative to: Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path
					relative to the workflow, mountpoint or node.
				</li>
				<li>Mountpoint: Allows you to choose a mountpoint. Whenever this is
					selected, a new drop-down menu appears to choose from available
					mountpoints.
				</li>
				<li>Custom URL: Uses the standard URL handler providing the ability
					to read a file from URLs (e.g. file, http or KNIME protocol).
					Browsing is disabled for this option.
				</li>
			</ul>
			It is possible to use other file systems with this node. Therefore,
			you have to enable the file system connection input port of this node
			by clicking the
			<b>...</b>
			in the bottom left corner of the node's icon and choose
			<i>Add File System Connection port</i>
			.
			<br />
			Afterwards, you can simply connect the desired connector node to the
			reader node. The file system connection will then be shown in the
			drop down menu.
		</option>
		<option name="File/URL">
			Enter a valid destination. Depending on the selected file system this
			is either a path (used by
			<i>Local File System</i>
			,
			<i>Relative to</i>
			,
			<i>Mountpoint</i>
			options and custom file systems added by specific connector nodes) or
			a URL (used by
			<i>Custom URL</i>
			option).
			<br />
			A path usually starts with a slash (/) character and does not contain
			a protocol.
			You can also choose a previously selected file from
			the
			drop-down list, or select a destination from the
			&quot;Browse...&quot; dialog (browsing is not available for custom
			URLs).
		</option>
		<option name="Timeout (ms)">
			Timeout in milliseconds when reading remote files.
			<tt>0</tt>
			means no
			timeout. In case it takes longer to connect to the host, the
			node fails to
			execute.
			<br />
			<i>Note</i>
			: This option is only active in case that the
			<i>Custom URL</i>
			or
			<i>Relative to</i>
			file system is selected. Other file
			systems don't use a timeout or the
			timeout is set directly in the specific
			connector node.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0" name="File system connection"
			group-identifier="File System Connection">
			The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="PMML Model">The PMML model just read.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>