<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="../csvreader.png" type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Simple File Reader</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Reads simple files of various formats.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
			This node reads local and remote files. It can be configured to read the most common formats. 
			If the file has a more complex structure, use the <i>File Reader</i> node which has more configuration
			options.<br />
			<br />
			When you open the node's configuration dialog and provide a filename, 
			it tries to guess
			the column specs by analyzing the content of the file. By default, only the first 50 rows are analyzed. 
			You can change this setting in the 'Limit Rows' tab. The file analysis can also be cut short by clicking
			the &quot;Quick scan&quot; button, which shows up if the analysis takes longer. If the file is not 
			analyzed completely, it could happen that
			the preview appears looking fine, but the execution of the node
			fails when it reads the lines it didn't analyze.
			Check the results of the analyzed file in the preview table and increase the number of rows scanned
			for spec if necessary.<br />
	        </p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Input location">
				Enter a valid file name or URL. You can also choose a previously read file from the drop-down list, 
				or select a file from the "Browse..." dialog.
			</option>	
			
			<option name="Column delimiter">
			  The character string delimiting columns. Use '\t' for tab character. Can get detected automatically.
			</option>
			<option name="Row delimiter">
	          The character string delimiting rows. Use '\n' for new line character. Can get detected automatically.
			</option>
			<option name="Quote char">
	          The quote character. Can get detected automatically. 
			</option>			
			<option name="Quote escape char">
	          The character is used for escaping quotes inside an already quoted value. Can get detected automatically.
			</option>
			<option name="Autodetect format">
	          By pressing this button, the "Column delimiter", "Row delimiter", "Quote char" and "Quote escape char" get 
	          automatically detected, though it is not guaranteed that the correct values are being detected.<br/>
	          The auto detection by default is based on the first 1024 * 1024 bytes of the selected file, but
	          can be adjusted by clicking the settings button next to this option.
	          The format can only be detected if the read number of bytes comprises one full data row and the 
	          autodetection will take at most 20 data rows into account. It is assumed that data rows are separated by
	          linebreaks.  Note that the "Skip first lines" option as well as the specified  "Comment char" will be used
	          when guessing the files format.
			</option>
			<option name="Comment char">
	          A character indicating line comments.
			</option>
			<option name="Has column header">
	          Select this box if the first row contains column name headers.  
			</option>
			<option name="Has row ID">
	          Select this box if the first column contains row IDs 
	          (no duplicates allowed).  
			</option>
			<option name="Support short data rows">
	          Select this box if some rows may be shorter than others (filled with missing values).
			</option>
			<option name="Skip empty data rows">
	          Select this box if rows without any content should not be in the output.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Advanced Options">
			<option name="Limit memory per column">
				If selected the memory per column is restricted to 1MB in order to prevent memory exhaustion. Uncheck
				this option to disable these memory restrictions.
			</option>
			<option name="Maximum number of columns">
				Sets the number of allowed columns (default 8192 columns) to
				prevent memory exhaustion. The node will fail if the number of columns
				exceed the set limit.
			</option>
			<option name="Quote options">
				<ul>
					<li>Remove quotes and trim whitespaces: Quotes will be removed from the value followed by trimming
					any leading/trailing whitespace.</li>
					<li>Keep quotes: The quotes of a value will be kept. Note: No trimming will be done inside the quotes.</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
			<option name="Replace empty quoted strings with missing values">
				Select this box if you want <b>quoted</b> empty strings to be replaced by missing value cell.
			</option>
			
		</tab>
	    <tab name="Limit Rows">
			<option name="Skip first lines">
	          If enabled, the specified number of lines are skipped in the input file before the parsing starts. 
	          Use this option to skip lines that do not fit in the table structure (e.g. mult-line comments) 
			</option>
			<option name="Skip first data rows">
	          If enabled, the specified number of valid data rows are skipped. This has no effect on which row will be 
	          chosen as column header.
			</option>
			<option name="Limit data rows">
	          If enabled, only the specified number of data rows are read. The column header row (if selected) is 
	          not taken into account.
			</option>
			<option name="Limit data rows scanned for spec">
	          If enabled, only the specified number of input <i>rows</i> are used to analyze the file (i.e to determine
	          the column types). This option is recommended for long files where the first <i>n</i> rows are 
	          representative for the whole file. The "Skip first data rows"
	          option has no effect on the scanning. Note also, that this option and the "Limit data rows" option are independent from each other
	          i.e. if the value in "Limit data rows" is smaller than the value specified here, we will still read as many rows as specified here.
			</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Simple File Reader Encoding">
	        <option name="Encoding">
	            To read a file that contains characters in a different encoding, you can select the character set in this tab (UTF-8, 
	            UTF-16, etc.), or specify any other encoding supported by your Java VM. The default value uses the default
	            encoding of the Java VM, which may depend on the locale or the Java property &quot;file.encoding&quot;
	        </option>
        </tab>	
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="File Table">
		  File being read with number and types of columns guessed automatically.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>   
        
        
        
        