<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="copymovefiles16x16.png" type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Copy/Move Files (Labs)</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Copies or moves files from a source (folder or file) to a specified destination folder.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node copies or moves files from a source (folder or file)
			to another folder. The node offers options to either copy or move a
			single file,
			a
			complete folder or the files in a selected folder, with
			the option
			to
			include subfolders, to a specified folder.
			If the "Delete
			source files
			(move)" option is checked the node performs
			a move
			operation for which
			the source files will be deleted after the
			copying
			process is done.
		</intro>
		<option name="Read from">
			Select a file system which stores the files/folders you want to
			copy/move.
			There are
			four default file system options to choose from:
			<br />
			<ul>
				<li>
					<i>Local File System:</i>
					Allows you to select a file/folder from your
					local system.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Mountpoint:</i>
					Allows you to read from a mountpoint.When selected, a new drop-down
					menu appears to choose the mountpoint. Unconnected mountpoints are
					greyed out but can still be selected (note that browsing is
					disabled in this case). Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the
					mountpoint to enable browsing. A mountpoint is displayed in red if
					it was previously selected but is no longer available. You won't be
					able to save the dialog as long as you don't select a valid i.e.
					known mountpoint.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Relative to:</i>
					Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path
					relative to the
					current mountpoint, current workflow or the current
					workflow's data
					area.
					When selected a new drop-down menu appears to choose which of
					the three
					options to use.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i>
					Allows to specify a URL (e.g. file://, http:// or knime://
					protocol). When selected, a spinner appears that allows you to
					specify the desired connection and read timeout in milliseconds. In
					case it takes longer to connect to the host / read the file, the
					node fails to execute.Browsing is disabled for this option.
				</li>
			</ul>
			To copy/move a file/folder from other file systems, click on
			<b>...</b>
			in the bottom left corner of the node icon followed by
			<i>Add File System Connection port</i>
			. Afterwards, connect the desired file system connector
			node to the
			newly added input port.
			The file system connection will then be shown
			in the drop-down menu.
			It is greyed out if the file system is not
			connected in which case you
			have to (re)execute the connector node
			first.
			Note: The default file systems listed above can't be selected
			if a file
			system is provided via the input port.
		</option>
		<option name="Mode">
			There are three different file/folder modes available:
			<ul>
				<li>
					<i>File:</i>
					Copies a single file.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Folder:</i>
					Copies a single folder with all its files and the underlying folder
					structure.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Files in folder:</i>
					Copies the files in a folder and creates the necessary folder structure as in the source folder.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</option>
		<option name="Filter options">
			Only displayed if the mode Files in folder is
			selected. Allows to specify
			which files should be included according
			to
			their file extension
			and/or name.It is also possible to include
			hidden
			files. The folder
			filter options enable you to specify which
			folders
			should be included
			based on their name and hidden status. Note
			that the
			folders
			themselves will not be included, only the files they
			contain.
		</option>
		<option name="Include subfolders">
			If this option is checked, the node will include
			all files from
			subfolders that satisfy the specified filter options.
			If left
			unchecked,
			only the files in the selected folder will be
			included and all files
			from subfolders are ignored.
		</option>
		<option name="Write to">
			This option allows you to specify a folder where
			you want to copy
			your file, files or folder in the end.
			This option has
			got the
			same options, except for the custom URL option, as the Read
			from option with regards
			to the file system
			options.
		</option>
		<option name="Create missing folders">
			Select if the folders of the selected output
			location should be created if
			they do not already exist. If this
			option is unchecked, the node
			will fail if a folder does not exist.
		</option>
		<option name="If exists">
			<ul>
				<li>
					<i>Overwrite:</i>
					Will replace any existing file.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Ignore:</i>
					Will ignore if a file already exists and continues the copying
					process.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Fail:</i>
					Will issue an error during the node's execution (to prevent
					unintentional overwrite).
				</li>
			</ul>
		</option>
		<option name="Include selected source folder">
			If this option is selected, a folder with the name of the last part
			of the selected path will get included in the copy process,otherwise
			only the contents of the specified folder will get included in the
			archive. This option does not work if only a single file should
			be copied or if the selected folder path ends with <b>..</b> or <b>.</b>.
			If it is not possible to include the source folder the dialog will
			show you an error message and the node will fail during execution.
		</option>
		<option name="Delete source files / folders (move)">
			If this option is checked all files which have
			been
			successfully copied
			to the destination folder
			will be deleted in
			the
			source
			folder. The
			output contains an
			additional column indicating
			if
			the file
			has been
			deleted (true) or not (false).
			<b>Note</b>
			Folders only get deleted when the Folder option is used.
		</option>
		<option name="Fail on unsuccessful deletion">
			If the 'Delete source files (move)' option is
			activated and something goes wrong during the deletion process the
			node will fail. This option is only available if the before mentioned
			option is selected.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>


	<ports>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0"
			name="Source file system connection"
			group-identifier="Source File System Connection">
			The source file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0"
			name="Destination file system connection"
			group-identifier="Destination File System Connection">
			The destination file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Copied files table">The files which should be copied with
			a source path column, destination path column, a folder identifier column
			and a deleted source column.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>