<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./file_system_connector.png"
	type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">

    <name>Local File System Connector</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Provides a file system connection with access to the file system of the local machine. 
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
         <intro>
            <p>This node provides access to the file system of the local machine. The resulting output port allows downstream nodes to access
            <i>files</i>, e.g. to read or write, or to perform other file system operations (browse/list files, copy, move, ...).
            </p>
            
            <p><b>Note:</b>In many cases it is not necessary to use this connector node to access the local file system. Nodes that require
            file system access (e.g. the File Reader node) typically provide local file system access, for example by choosing <i>Read from</i> >
            <i>Local File System.</i> The purpose of this connector node is that the <i>working directory</i> can be chosen, which makes file access with <i>relative</i> paths more
            convenient.  
            </p>
            
            <p><b>Path syntax:</b>The path syntax is identical to the one used by the operating system of the machine where this node is running, e.g.
            on Windows a path could look like <tt>C:\Users\joe</tt>.
            </p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Settings">
            <option name="Use custom working directory">
                Whether to set a custom working directory or not. Unless this option is set, the working directory will be the home directory of the
                current operating system user.
            </option>

	        <option name="Working directory">
		        Specify the <i>working directory</i> of the resulting file system connection, using the <b>Path syntax</b> explained above. The working
		        directory must be specified as an absolute path, for example <tt>C:\Users\joe</tt>. A working directory allows downstream nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i>
		        paths.
		    </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Local File System Connection">
             Local File System Connection
        </outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
