<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./delete16x16.png" type="Other"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Delete Files/Folders</name>

	<shortDescription>
        Deletes selected files as well as folders folders.
    </shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node deletes the files or folders at a specified location. The location may be a remote location.
			Folders will also be deleted if they still contain files.
		</intro>
		<option name="Read from">
			Select a file system on which you want to delete file(s) or folder(s). There are three default file system
			options to choose from:
			<br />
			<ul>
				<li>
					<i>Local File System:</i>
					Allows you to delete a file/folder from your local system.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Mountpoint:</i>
					Allows you to delete a file/folder on a mountpoint. When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to 
					choose the mountpoint. Unconnected mountpoints are grayed out but can still be selected (note that
					browsing is disabled in this case). Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable
					browsing. A mountpoint is displayed in red, if it was previously selected but is no longer 
					available. You won't be able to save the dialog as long as you don't select a valid i.e. known
					mountpoint.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Relative to:</i>
					Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path that should get deleted relative to the current
					mountpoint, current workflow or the current workflow's data area. When selected a new drop-down menu
					appears to choose which of the three options to use.
				</li>
			</ul>
			To read from other file systems, click on <b>...</b> in the bottom left corner of the node icon followed by
			<i>Add File System Connection port</i>. Afterwards, connect the desired file system connector node to the
			newly added input port. The file system connection will then be shown in the drop-down menu. It is grayed
			out if the file system is not connected in which case you have to (re)execute the connector node first.
			Note: The default file systems listed above can't be selected if a file system is provided via the input
			port.
		</option>
		<option name="Mode">
			Select whether you want to delete a single file, a folder or
			multiple files in a folder. When deleting files in a folder, you can set filters to specify which
			files and subfolders to include (see below).
		</option>
		<option name="Filter options">
			Only displayed if the mode <i>Files in folder</i> is selected. Allows to specify which files should be
			deleted according to their file extension and/or name. It is also possible to delete hidden files. The
			folder filter options enable you to specify from which folders the files should be deleted based on their
			name and hidden status. Note that the folders themselves will not be deleted, only the files they contain.
		</option>
		<option name="Include subfolders">
			If this option is checked, the node will delete all files from subfolders that satisfy the specified filter
			options. If left unchecked, only the files in the selected folder will be included and all files from
			subfolders are ignored.
		</option>
		<option name="File or Folder">
			Enter a path to a file or folder. The
			required syntax of a path depends on the chosen file system, such as &quot;C:\path\to\file&quot; (Local
			File System on Windows) or &quot;/path/to/file&quot; (Local File System on Linux/MacOS and Mountpoint). For
			file systems connected via input port, the node description of the respective connector node describes the
			required path format. You can also choose a previously selected file/folder from the drop-down list, or
			select a location from the &quot;Browse...&quot; dialog. Note that browsing is disabled in some cases:
			<ul>
				<li>
					<i>Mountpoint:</i>
					Browsing is disabled if the selected mountpoint isn't connected. Go to the KNIME Explorer and
					connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>File systems provided via input port:</i>
					Browsing is disabled, if the connector node hasn't been executed since the workflow has been opened.
					(Re)execute the connector node to enable browsing.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</option>
		<option name="Abort if delete fails">
			If this option is checked, the node will abort if one of the files could not be deleted. If it is unchecked
			the output table will contain a column that indicates if a file/folder got successfully deleted or not.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0" name="File System Connection"
			group-identifier="File System Connection">
			The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<outPort name="Output table" index="0">
			Table containing the list of files that have been deleted. If deletion is allowed to fail, there is an
			additional column, that will indicate if the deletion was successful or not.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>