<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./file_system_connector.png"
	type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">

    <name>KNIME Space Connector</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Provides a file system connection to access a KNIME Hub space.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
         <intro>
            <p>Provides a file system connection with access to a KNIME Hub space, for example the "Private" space on "My-KNIME-Hub".
            It is also possible to always connect to the space that contains the current workflow.
            The resulting output port allows downstream nodes to access <i>files</i>, e.g. to read or write, or to perform other file system operations
            (browse/list files, copy, move, ...) in the selected space. Files outside the configured space cannot be accessed.
            </p>
            
            <p><b>Path syntax:</b> Paths for this connector are specified with a UNIX-like syntax such as /myfolder/myfile. An absolute
            path consists of:
                <ol>
                    <li>A leading slash ("/").</li>
                    <li>Followed by the path to the file ("myfolder/myfile" in the above example).</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            
        </intro>
        <tab name="Settings">
            <option name="Space selection">
                Specify the <i>space</i> to access.
                
                <ul>
                <li>
                <b>Current space:</b> If chosen, the file system connection will give access to the space that contains the <i>current workflow.</i> If you
                are not using this connector node, this option is equivalent to choosing <i>Read from</i> > <i>Relative to</i> > <i>Current space.</i>
                </li>

                <li>
                <b>Other space:</b> If chosen, the file system connection will give access to the selected space
                </li>
                </ul> 
            </option>

            <option name="Hub mountpoint">
                If the <i>Other space</i> option is selected, this option allows to specify a mountpoint that connects to a KNIME Hub. 
                Unconnected mountpoints are greyed out  and can still be selected, but you need to go to the KNIME Explorer and connect the mountpoint
                before executing this node. A mountpoint is displayed in red if it was previously selected but is no longer available.
            </option>
            
            <option name="Space">
                If the <i>Other space</i> option is selected, this option allows to specify a <i>space</i> within the currently selected mountpoint.
            </option>

	        <option name="Working directory">
		        Specify the <i>working directory</i> of the resulting file system connection, using the <b>Path syntax</b> explained above. The working
		        directory must be specified as an absolute path. A working directory allows downstream nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i>
		        paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading slash. The default working directory is "/".
		    </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="File System Connection">
             File system connection to the current space, or the selected space.
        </outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
