<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./ColumnAutoTypeCaster.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.6" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.6 http://knime.org/node/v3.6.xsd">
	<name>Column Auto Type Cast</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Converts a column of type String to a Numeric or Date
		type, if and only if all entries could be converted.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
            This node determines the most specific type in the configured string columns and changes the column
            types accordingly. The type order is to first check if the values are dates, then integer, long, double, and
            finally string. For dates a custom format can be specified.
		</intro>

		
        <tab name="Manual Selection">
			<option name="Include">
				This list contains the names of those columns in the input table
				to be included in the output table.
			</option>
			
			<option name="Exclude">
				This list contains the names of those columns in the input table
				to be excluded from the output table.
			</option>

            <option name="Filter">
                Use one of these fields to filter either the Include or Exclude
                list for certain column names or name substrings.
            </option>
            
            <option name="Buttons">
                Use these buttons to move columns between the Include and Exclude 
                list. Single-arrow buttons will move all selected columns.
                Double-arrow buttons will move all columns (filtering is taken into
                account).
            </option>
            
            <option name="Enforce Inclusion">
                Select this option to enforce the current inclusion list to stay
                the same even if the input table specification changes. If some
                of the included columns are not available anymore, a warning
                is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
                exclusion list.)
            </option>

            <option name="Enforce Exclusion">
                Select this option to enforce the current exclusion list to stay
                the same even if the input table specification changes. If some
                of the excluded columns are not available anymore, a warning
                is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
                inclusion list.)
            </option>
        </tab>

        <tab name="Wildcard/Regex Selection">
        	<option name="">
				Type a search pattern which matches columns to move into the
				Include list. You can use either Wildcards ('?' matching any
				character, '*' matching a sequence of any characters) or Regex.
				You can specify whether your pattern should be case sensitive.
			</option>
        </tab>

		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Choose a date format">Choose or enter a date pattern. (y: Year, M: Month
				in year, d: Day in month, H: Hour in day, m: Minute in hour, s:
				Second in minute, S: Millisecond)
			</option>

			<option name="Missing value pattern">Choose or enter a missing value pattern. &lt;none&gt; is the default pattern 
				and &lt;empty&gt; represents the empty string. The entered string pattern is applied to all included columns.		
			</option>

			<option name="Quickscan">Check this checkbox if you want to speed up the node. The node will determine the 
				most specific type based on the first 1000 rows. 1000 is the default for the "number of rows to consider" 
				field. <br/>
				Note: With quickscan enabled this node could fail during execute. 
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>


	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input">Arbitrary input data.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Type-casted columns">
			Input data with type-casted columns.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Type information">Information about the chosen type casting.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
