<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="explainer_icon.png" type="LoopStart"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.6"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.6 http://knime.org/node/v3.6.xsd">
	<name>LIME Loop Start</name>

	<shortDescription>Start node for a LIME loop
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				LIME stands for Local Interpretable Model-agnostic Explanations.
				It tries to explain individual predictions of a black-box model by training a local surrogate
				model that is easier to understand (e.g. a linear model).
				The intuition behind this approach is that a globally non-linear model might actually be
				linear within a small local region of the feature space.
				In order to learn such a local surrogate model, LIME creates for a single row of interest a dataset of perturbed rows, predicts it with the black-box model
				and then learns a local surrogate that approximates the predictions of the black-box model.
				For more details on the algorithm please see the paper <i>"Why Should I Trust You?" Explaining the Predictions of Any Classifier</i> by Ribeiro et al.
			</p>
			
			<h3>Usage</h3>
			<p>
				The top input of this node contains the rows of interest for which the predictions of your model should be explained.
				Each row in the top table corresponds to one loop iteration, so its size will directly affect the runtime of the loop.
				The bottom input table is used for sampling which in this case means that column statistics (e.g. mean and standard deviation) are calculated
				for all of the feature columns. These statistics are later used to sample new values for the feature columns.
			</p>
			<p>
				In each iteration of the loop one row of interest is explained.
				This node produces two tables used for these explanations.
				The top table contains rows which are created by sampling according to the
				statistics of the feature columns in the sampling table.
				Note that numeric columns (including bit and byte vectors)
				are assumed to be normally distributed. This table has to be predicted with the Predictor node appropriate
				for your model at hand.
				The bottom table is meant for the training of a local surrogate model (e.g. a linear model).
				It differs from the top table in the following:
				<ol>
					<li>Nominal feature columns are replaced by Double columns where a 1.0 indicates that the sampled value matches of the row of interest.</li>
					<li>Bit and byte vector columns are split up into multiple columns, one for each element.</li>
					<li>A weight column is appended that indicates how similar the sampled row is two the row of interest.A higher value indicates greater similarity.</li>
				</ol>
				
				The loop body should do the following:
				<ol>
					<li>Predict the top table with the black-box model.</li>
					<li>Append the prediction column(s) to the bottom table.</li>
					<li>Train a local surrogate model that uses the features from the bottom table, weights each row according to the weight column and approximates the predictions of the black box model.
					The currently recommended Learner for this task is the H2O Generalized Linear Model Learner (Regression).</li>
					<li>Extract and collect the local explanations from the local surrogate model (e.g. the linear coefficients) in one of our Loop End nodes.</li>
				</ol>
			</p>

			<h3>Note on vector columns</h3>
			<p>
				Since the number of elements in a vector column is not known during configuration, the spec for the second table can't be generated if vectors are among the feature columns.
				In this case down-stream nodes can only be configured once this node has been executed.
			</p>
		</intro>

		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Feature columns">
				The columns that contain features your model requires.
				These columns will be contained in the top table that has to be predicted by your model.
			</option>

			<option name="Explanation set size">
				The number of rows to use for learning the local
				surrogate model for a single incoming row of interest.
			</option>
			<option name="Sample around instances">
				If checked, samples for numerical columns are drawn around the value of the current row of interest.
				Otherwise samples are drawn around the mean of the feature (which is calculated from the sampling table).
			</option>
			<option name="Use seed">
				Using a seed allows to reproduce the results of
				the loop. If this box is checked the seed displayed in the text box
				is used, otherwise a new seed is generated for each
				execution. The
				new button allows to generate a new random seed.
			</option>
			<option name="Manual kernel width">
				The default kernel width LIME uses for its exponential kernel is <i>sqrt(number of features) * 0.75</i>.
				By checking this box, the manually specified kernel width is used instead.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table containing the rows to explain">
			Table containing the rows to explain.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Sampling data">
			Table containing rows used to perturb
			rows in the first table.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Predictable table">This table contains samples that have
			to be predicted by the predictor node corresponding to your
			particular model.</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Local surrogate model table">This table contains data to learn a
			local surrogate model including a weight column.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
