<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="createpathvariables.png" type="Other"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Create File/Folder Variables</name>
	<shortDescription>Creates paths to files/folders and exposes them as flow variables.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>

            <p>
			This node allows to create <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#path">path flow variables.</a> 
			This is done by selecting a base folder and then defining a list of paths pointing to
			files/folders relative to the base folder. After executing the node the specified list of paths is accessible for subsequent nodes
			via flow variables.
			</p>
			
			<p>
			<i>Note:</i>
			The default base folder is the <a href="https://docs.knime.com/2021-06/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#working-directory">
			working directory</a> of the <a href="https://docs.knime.com/2021-06/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#relative-to">
			workflow data area</a>, as defined by “.“ in the Folder field.
			</p>

            <p>
            <i>This node can access a variety of different</i>
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/2021-06/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#analytics-platform-file-systems"><i>file systems.</i></a> 
            <i>More information about file handling in KNIME can be found in the official</i> 
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html"><i>File Handling Guide.</i></a>
            </p>

		</intro>
		<option name="Create for">
			Select a file system to which your file names are related. There are three default file system options to
			choose from:
			<br />
			<ul>
				<li>
					<i>Local File System:</i>
					Allows you to select a folder on your local system.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Mountpoint:</i>
					Allows you to read from a mountpoint. When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to choose the
					mountpoint. Unconnected mountpoints are greyed out but can still be selected (note that browsing is
					disabled in this case). Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.
					A mountpoint is displayed in red if it was previously selected but is no longer available.
					You won't be able to save the dialog as long as you don't select a valid i.e. known mountpoint.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Relative to:</i>
					Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path relative to the current mountpoint, current 
					workflow or the current workflow's data area. When selected a new drop-down menu appears to choose
					which of the three options to use.
				</li>
			</ul>
			It is possible to use other file systems with this node. Therefore, you have to enable the file system
			connection input port of this node by clicking the <b>...</b> in the bottom left corner of the node's icon
			and choose <i>Add File System Connection port</i>.
			<br />
			Afterwards, you can simply connect the desired connector node to this node. The file system connection will
			then be shown in the drop-down menu. It is grayed out if the file system is not connected in which case you
			have to (re)execute the connector node first. Note: The default file systems listed above can't be selected
			if a file system is provided via the input port.
		</option>
		<option name="Folder">
			Enter a valid base location for your paths. The required syntax of a path depends on the chosen file
			system, such as &quot;C:\path\to\file&quot; (Local File System on Windows) or &quot;/path/to/file&quot;
			(Local File System on Linux/MacOS and Mountpoint). For file systems connected via input port, the node
			description of the respective connector node describes the required path format. You can also choose a 
			previously selected folder from the drop-down list, or select a location from the &quot;Browse...&quot;
			dialog. Note that browsing is disabled in some cases:
			<ul>
				<li>
					<i>Mountpoint:</i>
					Browsing is disabled if, the selected mountpoint isn't connected. Go to the KNIME Explorer and
					connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>File systems provided via input port:</i>
					Browsing is disabled, if the connector node hasn't been executed since the workflow has been opened.
					(Re)execute the connector node to enable browsing.
				</li>
			</ul>
            <i>The location can be exposed as or automatically set via a 
            </i><a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#path">
            <i>path flow variable.</i></a>
		</option>
		<option name="File/Folder variables">
			A list of file/folder locations that will form a path with the selected base folder. Enter the name of the
			flow variable in the <i>Variable name</i> column and write the name of the file/folder in the <i>Value</i>
			column. In case of a file also fill in the <i>File extension</i> column. These will be added to the path
			shown in the <i>Base location</i> column.  
		</option>
		<link
			href="https://www.knime.com/knime-introductory-course/chapter7/section1/creation-and-usage-of-flow-variables">
			KNIME E-Learning Course: Creation and usage of Flow Variables in
			a KNIME workflow
		</link>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort name="Input variables (optional)" index="0">
			Input variables (optional).
		</inPort>
		<dynInPort group-identifier="File System Connection"
			insert-before="0" name="File system connection">The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Flow Variables with path information">Flow Variables with path information.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>