<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Source" xmlns='http://knime.org/node/v4.1'
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>Example CSV Reader</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Simple CSV Reader to be used as a template
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p><i>This node supports the 
            </i><a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#path"><i>path flow variable.</i></a>
            <i> For further information about file handling in general see the 
            </i><a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html"><i>File Handling Guide.</i></a><br/></p>
            <p>
            Reads a CSV from a file or URL. Each column is String type.
            </p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Settings">
                <option name="Read from">
                Select a file system which stores the data you want to read. There are
                four default file system options to choose from:
                <br />
                <ul>
                    <li><i>Local File System:</i> Allows you to select a file/folder from your
                        local system.
                    </li>
                    <li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Allows you to read from a mountpoint.
                        When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to choose the mountpoint.
                        Unconnected mountpoints are greyed out but can still be selected (note that browsing is disabled in this case).
                        Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.
                        A mountpoint is displayed in red if it was previously selected but is no longer available.
                        You won't be able to save the dialog as long as you don't select a valid i.e. known mountpoint.
                    </li>
                    <li><i>Relative to:</i> Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path
                        relative to the current mountpoint, current workflow or the current workflow's data area.
                    When selected a new drop-down menu appears to choose which of the three options to use.
                    </li>
                    <li><i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i> Allows to specify a URL (e.g. file://, http:// or knime:// protocol). 
                        When selected, a spinner appears that allows you to specify the desired connection and read timeout in milliseconds.
                        In case it takes longer to connect to the host / read the file, the node fails to execute.
                        Browsing is disabled for this option.
                    </li>
                </ul>
                To read from other file systems, click on
                <b>...</b> in the bottom left corner of the node icon followed by
                <i>Add File System Connection port</i>. Afterwards, connect the desired file system connector
                node to the newly added input port. The file system connection will then be shown in the drop-down menu.
                It is greyed out if the file system is not connected in which case you have to (re)execute the connector node first.
                Note: The default file systems listed above can't be selected if a file system is provided via the input port.
            </option>
            <option name="Mode">
                Select whether you want to read a single file or multiple files in a folder.
                When reading files in a folder, you can set filters to specify which
                files and subfolders to include (see below).
            </option>
            <option name="Filter options">
                Only displayed if the mode <i>Files in folder</i> is selected.
                Allows to specify which files should be included according to their file extension and/or name.
                It is also possible to include hidden files.
                The folder filter options enable you to specify which folders should be included based on their name and hidden status.
                Note that the folders themselves will not be included, only the files they contain.
            </option>
            <option name="Include subfolders">
                If this option is checked, the node will include all files from subfolders that satisfy the specified filter options.
                If left unchecked, only the files in the selected folder will be included and all files from subfolders are ignored.
            </option>
            
            
            <option name="File, Folder or URL">
                Enter a URL when reading from <i>Custom/KNIME URL</i>, otherwise enter a path to a file or folder. The
                required syntax of a path depends on the chosen file system, such as &quot;C:\path\to\file&quot; (Local
                File System on Windows) or  &quot;/path/to/file&quot; (Local
                File System on Linux/MacOS and Mountpoint). For file systems connected via input port, the node
                description of the respective connector node describes the required path format.
                You can also choose a previously selected file/folder from the drop-down list, or select a location
                from the &quot;Browse...&quot; dialog.
                Note that browsing is disabled in some cases:
                <ul>
                    <li><i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i> Browsing is always disabled.</li>
                    <li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Browsing is disabled if the selected mountpoint isn't connected.
                    Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.</li>
                    <li><i>File systems provided via input port:</i>
                    Browsing is disabled if the connector node hasn't been executed since the workflow has been opened.
                    (Re)execute the connector node to enable browsing.</li>
                </ul>
                <i>The location can be exposed as or automatically set via a 
                </i><a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#path">
                <i>path flow variable.</i></a>
            </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <dynInPort insert-before="0" name="File system connection" group-identifier="File System Connection"> 
            The file system connection.
        </dynInPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="File Table">
          File being read separated by "," with String type.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
