<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./listfiles.png" type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>List Files/Folders (Labs) </name>
	<shortDescription>
		List files and/or folders contained in the selected folder.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			List files and/or folders contained in the selected folder.
		</intro>
		<option name="Read from">
				Select a file system which stores the files/folders you want to list. There are
				three default file system options to choose from:
				<br />
				<ul>
	                <li><i>Local File System:</i> Allows you to select a folder from your
	                    local system.
	                </li>
	                <li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Allows you to read from a mountpoint.
	                	When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to choose the mountpoint.
	                	Unconnected mountpoints are greyed out but can still be selected (note that browsing is disabled in this case).
	                	Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.
	                	A mountpoint is displayed in red if it was previously selected but no longer available.
	                	You won't be able to close save the dialog as long as you don't select a valid i.e. known mountpoint.
	                </li>
	                <li><i>Relative to:</i> Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path
						relative to the workflow or mountpoint.
	                When selected a new drop-down menu appears to choose which of the two options to use.
	                </li>
				</ul>
				To list files/folders from other file systems, click on
	            <b>...</b> in the bottom left corner of the node icon followed by
	            <i>Add File System Connection port</i>. Afterwards, connect the desired file system connector
	            node to the newly added input port.
	            The file system connection will then be shown in the drop-down menu.
	            It is greyed out if the file system is not connected in which case you have to (re)execute the connector node first.
				Note: The default file systems listed above can't be selected if a file system is provided via the input port.
			</option>
			<option name="Mode">
				There are three different file/folder listing modes available:
				<ul>
					<li><i>Files in folder:</i> Lists only files.</li>
					<li><i>Folders:</i> Lists only folders.</li>
					<li><i>Files and folders:</i> Lists both files and folders.</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
			<option name="Filter options">
				Allows to specify which files/folders should be included according to their file extension and/or name.
				It is also possible to include hidden files/folders.
			</option>
			<option name="Include subfolders">
				If this option is checked, the node will include all files/folders from subfolders that satisfy the specified filter options.
				If left unchecked, only the files/folders in the selected folder will be included and all files/folders from subfolders are ignored.
			</option>
			
			
			<option name="Folder">
				Allows you to specify the folder whose contents should be listed. The
				required syntax of a path depends on the chosen file system, such as &quot;C:\path\to\file&quot; (Local
				File System on Windows) or  &quot;/path/to/file&quot; (Local
	            File System on Linux/MacOS and Mountpoint). For file systems connected via input port, the node
	            description of the respective connector node describes the required path format.
				You can also choose a previously selected folder from the drop-down list, or select a location
				from the &quot;Browse...&quot; dialog.
				Note that browsing is disabled in some cases:
				<ul>
					<li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Browsing is disabled if the selected mountpoint isn't connected.
					Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.</li>
					<li><i>File systems provided via input port:</i>
					Browsing is disabled if the connector node hasn't been executed since the workflow has been opened.
					(Re)execute the connector node to enable browsing.</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
		
		
		<option name="Include parent folder">
			If selected the output contains the (selected) folder for which the files/folders are being listed.
		</option>
		<option name="Add folder identifier column">If selected the output contains an additional column indicating
			if the path points to a folder (<tt>true</tt>) or a file (<tt>false</tt>).
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<dynInPort group-identifier="File System Connection"
			insert-before="0" name="File system connection">The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="File/Folder List">List of files/folders.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
