<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./file_system_connector.png"
	type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">

    <name>KNIME Workflow Data Area Connector</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Provides a file system connection with access to the data area of the current KNIME workflow.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
         <intro>
            <p>Provides a file system connection with access to the data area of the current KNIME workflow.
            The resulting output port allows downstream nodes to access <i>files</i>, e.g. to read or write, or to perform other file system operations
            (browse/list files, copy, move, ...).
            </p>
            
            <p><b>Note:</b>In many cases it is not necessary to use this connector node. Nodes that require
            file system access (e.g. the File Reader node) already provide the same level of access by choosing <i>Read from</i> >
            <i>Relative To</i> > <i>Current workflow data area.</i>. The purpose of this connector node is to make file access with
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#path-syntax">relative paths</a>
            more flexible, by allowing to explicitly configure the 
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#working-directory">working
            directory</a> of the resulting file system connection. For example,
            this makes it easier to relocate (or change) the files that your workflow accesses, because you only need to change
            the working directory.
            </p>
            
            
            
        </intro>
        <tab name="Settings">
	        <option name="Working directory">
		        Specify the <i>working directory</i> of the resulting file system connection, using the <b>Path syntax</b> explained above. The working
		        directory must be specified as an absolute path. A working directory allows downstream nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i>
		        paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading slash. The default working directory is "/".
		    </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Workflow Data Area File System Connection">
             File system connection to the workflow data area of the current KNIME workflow.
        </outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
