<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="compress16x16.png" type="Other"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Compress Files/Folder (Labs)</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Compresses a file, a folder or files in folder to an archive.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node compresses files or a folder to an archive. 
			The archive format is determined by the file extension in the destination file selection. 
			All supported formats are selectable in the destination file browser. If a format is selected, the file extension gets appended to the entered filename automatically.
			<br />
			<br />
			Supported archive formats are:
			<ul>
				<li>.zip</li>
				<li>.jar</li>
				<li>.tar</li>
				<li>.tar.gz</li>
				<li>.tar.bz2</li>
				<li>.cpio</li>
				<li>.ar</li>
			</ul>
		</intro>

<option name="Read from">
			Select a file system from which you want to choose files/folders which should be added to an archive. There are four default file system
			options to choose from:
			<br />
			<ul>
				<li>
					<i>Local File System:</i>
					Allows you to pack an archive with files/folder from your local system.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Mountpoint:</i>
					Allows you to pack an archive with files/folder from a mountpoint. When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to 
					choose the mountpoint. Unconnected mountpoints are grayed out but can still be selected (note that
					browsing is disabled in this case). Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable
					browsing. A mountpoint is displayed in red, if it was previously selected but is no longer 
					available. You won't be able to save the dialog as long as you don't select a valid i.e. known
					mountpoint.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Relative to:</i>
					Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path of files/folder that should be packed to an archive relative to the current
					mountpoint, current workflow or the current workflow's data area. When selected a new drop-down menu
					appears to choose which of the three options to use.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i> 
					Allows to specify a URL (e.g. file://, http:// or knime:// protocol). 
	                When selected, a spinner appears that allows you to specify the desired connection and write timeout in milliseconds.
	                In case it takes longer to connect to the host / write the file, the node fails to execute.
	                Browsing is disabled for this option.
	            </li>
			</ul>
			To read from other file systems, click on <b>...</b> in the bottom left corner of the node icon followed by
			<i>Add ports</i> and <i>Source file system connection</i>. Afterwards, connect the desired file system connector node to the
			newly added input port. The file system connection will then be shown in the drop-down menu. It is grayed
			out if the file system is not connected in which case you have to (re)execute the connector node first.
			Note: The default file systems listed above can't be selected if a file system is provided via the input
			port.
		</option>
		<option name="Mode">
				Select whether you want to add single file, a folder or multiple files in a folder to an archive.
				When reading files in a folder, you can set filters to specify which
				files and subfolders to include (see below).
			</option>
			<option name="Filter options">
				Only displayed if the mode <i>Files in folder</i> is selected.
				Allows to specify which files should be included according to their file extension and/or name.
				It is also possible to include hidden files.
				The folder filter options enable you to specify which folders should be included based on their name and hidden status.
				Note that the folders themselves will not be included, only the files they contain.
			</option>
			<option name="Include subfolders">
				If this option is checked, the node will include all files from subfolders that satisfy the specified filter options.
				If left unchecked, only the files in the selected folder will be included and all files from subfolders are ignored.
			</option>
		<option name="File, Folder or URL">
			Enter a URL when reading from <i>Custom/KNIME URL</i>, otherwise enter a path to a file or folder. The
				required syntax of a path depends on the chosen file system, such as &quot;C:\path\to\file&quot; (Local
				File System on Windows) or  &quot;/path/to/file&quot; (Local
	            File System on Linux/MacOS and Mountpoint). For file systems connected via input port, the node
	            description of the respective connector node describes the required path format.
				You can also choose a previously selected folder from the drop-down list, or select a location
				from the &quot;Browse...&quot; dialog.
				Note that browsing is disabled in some cases:
				<ul>
					<li><i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i> Browsing is always disabled.</li>
					<li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Browsing is disabled if the selected mountpoint isn't connected.
					Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.</li>
					<li><i>File systems provided via input port:</i>
					Browsing is disabled if the connector node hasn't been executed since the workflow has been opened.
					(Re)execute the connector node to enable browsing.</li>
				</ul>
		</option>
		<option name="Include parent folder">
			If this option is selected, a folder with the name of the last part of the selected path will get included in the archive, 
			otherwise only the contents of the specified folder will get included in the archive.
			This option will get disabled, if only a single file should get packed into an archive or if the selected folder path ends with <b>..</b> or <b>.</b>.
		</option>
		<option name="Write to">
				Select a file system on which you want to save your archive file.
				There are four default file system options to choose from:
				<br />
				<ul>
					<li><i>Local File System:</i> Allows you to select a folder on your
	                    local system.
	                </li>
	                <li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Allows you to write to a mountpoint.
	                	When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to choose the mountpoint.
	                	Unconnected mountpoints are greyed out but can still be selected (note that browsing is disabled in this case).
	                	Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.
	                	A mountpoint is displayed in red if it was previously selected but is no longer available.
	                	You won't be able to save the dialog as long as you don't select a valid i.e. known mountpoint.
	                </li>
	                <li><i>Relative to:</i> Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path
						relative to the current mountpoint, current workflow or the current workflow's data area.
	                When selected a new drop-down menu appears to choose which of the three options to use.
	                </li>
	                <li>
					<i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i> 
					Allows to specify a URL (e.g. file://, http:// or knime:// protocol). 
	                When selected, a spinner appears that allows you to specify the desired connection and write timeout in milliseconds.
	                In case it takes longer to connect to the host / write the file, the node fails to execute.
	                Browsing is disabled for this option.
	            </li>
				</ul>
				It is possible to use other file systems with this node. Therefore,
				you have to enable the file system connection input port of this
				node
				by clicking the
				<b>...</b>
				in the bottom left corner of the node's icon and choose
				<i>Add ports</i> followed by <i>Destination file system connection</i>
				.
				<br />
				Afterwards, you can simply connect the desired connector node to this node.
				The file system connection will then be shown in the drop-down menu.
				It is grayed out if the file system is not connected in which case you have to (re)execute the connector node first.
				Note: The default file systems listed above can't be selected if a file system is provided via the input port.
			</option>
		<option name="File">
			Enter a valid path where the created archive should get saved. The
				required syntax of a path depends on the chosen file system, such as &quot;C:\path\to\file&quot; (Local
				File System on Windows) or  &quot;/path/to/file&quot; (Local
	            File System on Linux/MacOS and Mountpoint). For file systems connected via input port, the node
	            description of the respective connector node describes the required path format.
				You can also choose a previously selected folder from the drop-down list, or select a location
				from the &quot;Browse...&quot; dialog.
				Note that browsing is disabled in some cases:
				<ul>
					<li><i>Custom/KNIME URL:</i> Browsing is always disabled.</li>
					<li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Browsing is disabled if the selected mountpoint isn't connected.
					Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.</li>
					<li><i>File systems provided via input port:</i>
					Browsing is disabled if the connector node hasn't been executed since the workflow has been opened.
					(Re)execute the connector node to enable browsing.</li>
				</ul>
		</option>
		<option name="Create missing folders">Select if the folders of the selected
				output
				location should be created if they do not already exist. If
				this
				option is unchecked, the node will fail if a folder does not
				exist.
			</option>
			<option name="If exists">
				Specify the behavior of the node in case the output file already exists.
				<ul>
					<li><i>Overwrite:</i> Will replace any existing file.
					</li>
					<li><i>Ignore:</i> Will ignore existing files
					</li>
					<li><i>Fail:</i> Will issue an error during the node's execution (to prevent unintentional overwrite).
					</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0" name="Source File System Connection"
			group-identifier="Source File System Connection">
			The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0" name="Destination File System Connection"
			group-identifier="Destination File System Connection">
			The file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
