<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="unpivot.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.6" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.6 http://knime.org/node/v3.6.xsd">
	<name>Unpivoting</name>
	<shortDescription>      
		This node rotates the selected columns from the input table to rows and duplicates
		at the same time the remaining input columns by appending them to each corresponding output row. 
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node rotates the selected columns from the input table to rows and duplicates
			at the same time the remaining input columns by appending them to each corresponding output row. Example:
			<pre>
			Input:
				Value1 Value2 Value3 Extra1 Extra2 Extra3
			Output:
				Value1 Extra1 Extra2 Extra3
				Value2 Extra1 Extra2 Extra3
				Value3 Extra1 Extra2 Extra3
			</pre>
		</intro>

		<tab name="Value columns">      
			<option name="Include">
				This list contains the names of the columns that are rotated into one single column. 
			</option>
		</tab>

		<tab name="Retained columns">
			<option name="Include">
				This list contains the column names of the columns
				which are duplicated by the number of selected value columns.
			</option>
		</tab>

		<tab name="Manual Selection">
            <option name="Filter">
                Use one of these fields to filter either the Include or Exclude
                list for certain column names or name substrings.
            </option>
            
            <option name="Buttons">
                Use these buttons to move columns between the Include and Exclude 
                list. Single-arrow buttons will move all selected columns.
                Double-arrow buttons will move all columns (filtering is taken into
                account).
            </option>
            
            <option name="Enforce Inclusion">
                Select this option to enforce the current inclusion list to stay
                the same even if the input table specification changes. If some
                of the included columns are not available anymore, a warning
                is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
                exclusion list.)
            </option>

            <option name="Enforce Exclusion">
                Select this option to enforce the current exclusion list to stay
                the same even if the input table specification changes. If some
                of the excluded columns are not available anymore, a warning
                is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
                inclusion list.)
            </option>
        </tab>

        <tab name="Wildcard/Regex Selection">
        	<option name="">
				Type a search pattern which matches columns to move into the
				Include list. You can use either Wildcards ('?' matching any
				character, '*' matching a sequence of any characters) or Regex.
				You can specify whether your pattern should be case sensitive.
			</option>
        </tab>

        <tab name="Type Selection">
        	<option name="">
				Select the column types that you want to include. Column types
				that are currently not present are depicted in italic.
			</option>
        </tab>

		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Enable hiliting">
				Select, if hiliting is enabled between input and output data.
			</option>
			<option name="Skip rows containing missing cells">
				Skip all rows containing missing cells in selected value column(s).
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Data table">
			Input table with at least on value
			column for the unpivoting operation.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Unpivoting table">
			Unpivoting table with duplicated columns together with one
			rotated value column and their corresponding column names.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
