<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./extract_context_props.png" type="Source" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>Extract Context Properties</name>
	<shortDescription>Reads workflow context related properties, 
	   including workflow name and the logged in user.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>Reads workflow context related properties, 
            including workflow name and the logged in user. The fields are 
            extracted using the KNIME workflow context.<br />
            The properties are:
            <ul>
                <li><i>context.workflow.name</i> The name of the workflow.</li>
                <li><i>context.workflow.path</i> The mount-point-relative path to the workflow.</li>
                <li><i>context.workflow.absolute-path</i> The absolute path in the filesystem to the workflow.</li>
                <li><i>context.workflow.user</i>
                    User ID of the authenticated user if executed on KNIME Server/Hub, the system user otherwise.</li>
                <li><i>context.workflow.temp.location</i> The location for temporary files of the workflow job.</li>
                <li><i>context.workflow.author.name</i> Name of the workflow author (creator).</li>
                <li><i>context.workflow.last.editor.name</i>
                    Name of the person who edited the workflow last (on last save).</li>
                <li><i>context.workflow.creation.date</i> Date when the workflow was saved the first time.</li>
                <li><i>context.workflow.last.time.modified</i> Date when workflow was saved last.</li>
                <li><i>context.job.id</i> The job's ID when run on Server/Hub, otherwise will be empty.</li>
                <li><i>context.workflow.username</i>
                    User name of the authenticated user if executed on KNIME Server/Hub, the system user otherwise.</li>
                <li><i>context.workflow.executor.version</i> Version of the KNIME AP executing the workflow.</li>
                <li><i>context.workflow.hub.item.id</i> Item ID of the workflow in the Hub's repository.</li>
                <li><i>context.workflow.hub.space.id</i>
                    Item ID of the space containing the workflow in the Hub's repository.</li>
                <li><i>context.workflow.hub.space.path</i>
                    The mount-point-relative path to the root of the space containing the workflow.</li>
                <li><i>context.workflow.hub.api.base-url</i>
                    The base URL of the Hub's API when stored on Hub, otherwise will be empty.</li>
                <li><i>context.job.account.id</i>
                    ID of the account that owns the job when run on Hub, otherwise will be empty.</li>
                <li><i>context.job.account.name</i>
                    Name of the account that owns the job when run on Hub, otherwise will be empty.</li>
            </ul>
            More properties may be added in the future.
        </intro>
        <option name="Extract all available properties">
            If selected all available context properties are extracted.
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="Context Properties">
			Context properties as flow variables.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>