<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="column_merger.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>Column Merger</name>

    <shortDescription>Merges two columns into one by choosing the cell 
        that is non-missing.  
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
              Merges two columns into one by choosing the cell that is 
              non-missing. The configuration dialog allows you to choose a 
              primary and a secondary column. The output of the node will
              be a new column (or a replacement of the selected input columns),
              whereby the output value for each row will be
              <ul>
                <li>the value in the primary column if it is not missing,</li>
                <li>the value in the secondary column otherwise.</li>
              </ul>
            </p>
            <p>
			  Note that the output value might be missing if and only if the 
			  secondary column contains a missing value. Also note that the type
			  of the output column is a super type of both selected inputs, i.e.
			  if you choose to merge a number and a string column, the output
			  column will have a very general data type.
            </p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Primary column">
            The column with the value that will be used, unless it is missing. 
        </option>
        <option name="Secondary column">
            The column with the value that will be used if it is missing in the primary column.
        </option>
        <option name="Replace/append columns">
            Choose where to put the result column:
            <ul>
            <li><b>Replace primary and delete secondary</b>: Replace the primary column with the merge result and remove the secondary column.</li>
            <li><b>Replace primary</b>: Replace the primary column with the merge result and keep the secondary column.</li>
            <li><b>Replace secondary</b>: Keep the primary column and replace the secondary column with the merge result.</li>
            <li><b>Append as new column</b>: Append a new column with the name provided below.</li>
            </ul>
        </option>
        <option name="New column name">The name for the new column.</option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input">Input with two columns to merge.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Input with amended column">
            Input along with the merged column.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
    <keywords>
    	<keyword>Coalesce</keyword> <!-- SQL name -->
    </keywords>
</knimeNode>
