<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="../transferfiles16x16.png" type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Transfer Files (Table input)</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Transfers files/folders taken from an input table to a specified destination folder.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
            <p><i>This node supports the 
            </i><a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html#path"><i>path flow variable</i></a>
            <i> to specify the source and destination location. To convert the created path column to a string column which is 
            required by some nodes that have not been migrated yet you can use the </i>
            <a href="https://kni.me/n/ZLCisQlHCzW4IiZG"><i>Path to String</i></a><i> node.
             For further information about file handling in general see the 
            </i><a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html"><i>File Handling Guide.</i></a><br/></p>
            
            <p>
			This node copies or moves files from a source (folder or file) to another folder. The node offers options to
			either specify the destination based on a column in the input table or via a file chooser. If the 
			"Delete source files (move)" option is checked the node performs a move operation for which the source
			files will be deleted after the copying process is done.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Source column">
			Allows to select the column containing the paths to the files/folders that must be copied/moved.
		</option>
		<option name="From table">
			Allows to select the column containing the destination, i.e., the new location and names of the 
			files/folders to be copied/moved. 
			<br/>
			<i>Note:</i> If the source references a file/folder the destination also has to be a file/folder.  
		</option>
		<option name="From file chooser">
			This option allows you to specify a folder where you want to copy/move the (source) files/folders to.
			There are three default file system options to choose from:
			<br />
			<ul>
				<li><i>Local File System:</i> Allows you to select a location on your
                    local system.
                </li>
                <li><i>Mountpoint:</i> Allows you to write to a mountpoint.
                	When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to choose the mountpoint.
                	Unconnected mountpoints are greyed out but can still be selected (note that browsing is disabled in 
                	this case). Go to the KNIME Explorer and connect to the mountpoint to enable browsing.
                	A mountpoint is displayed in red if it was previously selected but is no longer available.
                	You won't be able to save the dialog as long as you don't select a valid, i.e. known, mountpoint.
                </li>
                <li><i>Relative to:</i> Allows you to choose whether to resolve the path
					relative to the current mountpoint, current workflow, or the current workflow's data area.
                When selected, a new drop-down menu appears to choose which of the three options to use.
                </li>
			</ul>
			It is possible to use other file systems with this node. For this you have to enable the file system
			connection input port of this node by clicking the <b>...</b> in the bottom left corner of the node's icon
			and choose <i>Add Destination File System Connection</i>.
			<br />
			Afterwards, you can simply connect the desired connector node to this node. The file system connection will
			then be shown in the drop-down menu. It is greyed out if the file system is not connected, in which case
			you have to (re)execute the connector node first. Note: The default file systems listed above can't be
			selected if a file system is provided via the input port.
		</option>
		<option name="Create missing folders">
			Select if the folders of the selected output location should be created if they do not already exist. If
			this option is unchecked, the node will fail if a folder does not exist.
		</option>
		<option name="Transfer policy">
			<ul>
				<li>
					<i>Overwrite:</i>
					Will replace any existing file.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Overwrite if newer:</i>
					Will replace any existing file if the source file's last modified date is after the destination
					file's last modified date, otherwise the file will not be overwritten and the copy process is
					being continued.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Ignore:</i>
					Will ignore if a file already exists and continues the copying process.
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>Fail:</i>
					Will issue an error during the node's execution (to prevent unintentional overwrite).
				</li>
			</ul>
		</option>		
		<option name="Source folder truncation">
			Depending on the selected strategy the folder containing the files/folders to copy/move is being truncated
			differently, i.e., this option allows to modify the resulting (destination) folder structure. For the 
			remainder assume that <tt>folder/other/</tt> is the selected folder and it contains the file 
			<tt>folder/other/subfolder/file.txt</tt>
			<ul>
				<li><i>Keep full path:</i>
					This selection ensures that the folder's path is not being truncated, i.e., the destination folder
					will contain the entry <tt>folder/other/subfolder/file.txt</tt>
				</li>
				<li><i>Keep source folder only:</i>
					This selection ensures that anything preceding the source folder's name is being truncated,
					i.e., the destination folder will contain the entry <tt>other/subfolder/file.txt</tt>
				</li>
				<li><i>Truncate full path:</i>
					This selection ensures that the folder's path is being fully truncated, i.e., the destination folder
					will contain the entry <tt>subfolder/file.txt</tt>.
				</li>
				<li><i>Truncate:</i>
					This selection truncates the first occurrence in the folder's path matching the regular expression,
					i.e., the destination folder will contain the entry <tt>folder/subfolder/file.txt</tt>
					given the regular expression <tt>other.*</tt>.
				</li>
			</ul> 
			If it is not possible to apply the selected truncation strategy the node will fail during execution.
		</option>
		<option name="Delete source files / folders">
			If this option is checked all files which have been successfully copied to the destination folder
			will be deleted in the source folder. The output contains an additional column indicating if the file has
			been deleted (true) or not (false).
		</option>
		<option name="Fail on unsuccessful deletion">
			If the 'Delete source files (move)' option is activated and something goes wrong during the deletion process
			the node will fail. This option is only available if the before mentioned option is selected.
		</option>
		<option name="Verbose output">
			If selected the output will not only show the folder that has been copied/moved but also all the 
			files/folders it contains.
		</option>
		<option name="Fail if source does not exist">
			If selected the node will fail in case the source file/folder to copy/move does not exist.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
	<inPort name="Input table" index="0">
			The input table containing a Path column.
		</inPort>
		<dynInPort insert-before="0" name="Source file system connection" 
		group-identifier="Source File System Connection">
			The source file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<dynInPort insert-before="1" name="Destination file system connection"
			group-identifier="Destination File System Connection">
			The destination file system connection.
		</dynInPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Copied files table">
			A table revealing the files/folders which were copied/moved.  It contains a source and destination path 
			column as well as a folder identifier, and a copy status column. Additionally, if <i>Delete source files /
			folders</i> is selected the output contains a source deleted column and if <i>Fail if source does not
			exist</i> is unchecked the output has a source exist(ed) column.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>